<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://zacharybell.net///feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://zacharybell.net///" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-09-15T13:49:16-06:00</updated><id>https://zacharybell.net///</id><title type="html">ZacharyBell.net</title><subtitle>Only the finest in novels, short stories and blog-like materials.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Demonist</title><link href="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/10/10/the-demonist.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Demonist" /><published>2015-10-10T17:10:08-06:00</published><updated>2015-10-10T17:10:08-06:00</updated><id>https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/10/10/the-demonist</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/10/10/the-demonist.html">&lt;h3&gt;On Demons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stripped of unnecessary foofraw—the chanting, the hooded robes, the goat entrails—summoning a demon is a two-step process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step one: learn a demon’s true name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step two: say that name out loud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know the name, speak the name. Now you have a demonic butler.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;Or, more likely, now you’re being disemboweled by a cranky minion of Hell&lt;/span&gt; Putting on a condom requires a more extensive diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, as with everything demonic, there’s a catch. Actually, there are a two, broadly speaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, when tonsures were in fashion and most people dropped out of school the moment they dropped out of the womb, obtaining a true name did pose something of a challenge. Would-be summoners had to venture into tombs and forgotten temples. They poured over obscure texts tattooed onto the backs of mute slaves and looked to chicken entrails for the faintest clues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, thanks to the internet, true names are available by the dozen, from the lowliest denizens to the very masters of Hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings us to step two, the detail in which the devil dwells: speaking the name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bethannal, Lord of the Fifth Pit&amp;#39;s true name has been known for millennia. It was actually one of the first true names known by men, because Bethannal writes her own true name on her banners and brands it onto her underlings. Even so, Bethannal has never been summoned by a mortal and probably never will be, because her true name is Cik&amp;#39;dasra&amp;#39; Diq&amp;#39; Drisgz&amp;uuml; gatizzyrchs’ Ahrhch’ &amp;Ograve;ehp &amp;#39;Caxxcuxst, which, you might have noticed, is a grad mal seizure, phonetically speaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet demons &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; summoned. They’re summoned with a fair regularity, in fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there are a lot humans and they’re always making stupid noises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, a man nailing some sheet metal to the roof of his hut hits his thumb with a hammer and the sound of his feet hopping down on the metal combined with his florid cursing in Urdu summons a couple of hellflies. Or a woman, demonstrating a malfunctioning garbage disposal for her landlord, trips on a bag of board games that were supposed to go to Goodwill, screams, knocks over a wine rack while falling face-first into a mostly-complete set of Sorry! pieces and suddenly there’s a pissed-off greater selkie in the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, accident is the surest way to summon a demon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So begins begins the story of Timothy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;On Timothy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he summoned his first demon, Timothy Martin was twenty-eight years old and working as a short order cook in Akron, Ohio, which should serve as a convenient shorthand to establish Timothy’s position at the losing tail of the American bell curve in all things actuarial or demographical. To further elaborate, he was awkward, loud when he wasn’t sullen, oily about the T-zone, nearsighted, and actually dumb enough to think he might be smart. A three-and-a-half-maybe-four-out-of-ten gene propagation wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy was also a geek. Which is fine. Good even, as he happened to be born into one of those rare periods of history where the geeks temporarily inherit the mainstream and therefore the Earth. Unfortunately for Timothy, his particular patch of geekdom was not computers or math, which could have led to lucrative employment, nor was it comic books—useful at least for reminding confused girlfriends who the purple-faced fellow in the cape is during a midnight showing of &lt;em&gt;The Avengers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For lack of an exact appellation Timothy was a hippie or a pagan or an elf. A historical reenactor. A tapestry fancier. A mystic seeker. A horoscope composer. A man who desperately wanted to see faeries, a poet who believed that the true language of love is Elvish. A wearer of tights and of fey little boots and an owner of velvet capes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started with the usual gateway drugs, like &lt;em&gt;Dungeons and Dragons&lt;/em&gt; and maybe some LARPing on the the weekends, but then he got a taste of the harder stuff. &lt;em&gt;The Silmarillion&lt;/em&gt;. Lay line maps, tinctures in little glass bottles, spells written on scrolls and sealed by the power of the equinox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which, again, fine. Geeks of this stripe often thrive. Darwin’s theories would suggest an end to RenFests if this weren’t the case. None of this is meant as a critique of Timothy’s hobbies. It’s merely important that you realize Timothy didn’t really believe in magic, but at the same time, he completely believed in magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he was right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first link in the chain that would ultimately bind Timothy to his destiny was forged when Timothy’s manager at the Denny’s Restaurant sat him down to tell him that his food wastage was too high. Specifically, his bacon wastage. This calculation had been done at corporate by a computer that knew the weight of the bacon going into the kitchen and the number of plates coming out during his shifts and the two numbers did not match up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The manager’s name was Judy and she was a big, tired, kind-hearted woman incapable of delivering a rancorous chewing out, but corporate had mandated a chewing out, so she would do it and then check it off the list and go about vacuuming the carpet because all that separated her from her employees was a slightly more verbose nametag and three dollars an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Am I fired?” Timothy asked. He had his duffel bag with him, and his coat, so if she was going to fire him at least he wouldn’t have to walk back to his locker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No,” Judy sighed, “you’re not fired.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh,” Timothy said, both relief and disappointment in his voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you sneaking a few strips while you’re on the line? Are you just screwing up a lot?” Judy asked, “Do you need to watch the training video again?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry,” Timothy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t specifically an admission of guilt or an cry for remedial bacon-frying instruction, but it was something, so after a long silence, Judy decided to declare victory and stood up from the booth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s get that number back towards zero next month,” Judy said, meaning the  bacon input-to-output ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure,” Timothy said, simultaneously sullen and obsequious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judy patted him on the shoulder. Timothy had been working at the Denny’s for almost five years and she always felt sorry for the long-timers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he walked across the empty dining room, Timothy happened to see a plastic bag lying on the bench seat of a booth. There was something in that bag. Something flattishly cuboidal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He bent over the table and picked the bag up. The object inside was heavy enough to make him grunt a little from the effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps as he put his hand into that plastic bag, he heard, distant but rising, the clarion of destiny beckoning and, for a moment Timothy hesitated. There was something terrible in that bag. He felt a sharp prick against his adrenal glands that told him to drop whatever it was and run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But he didn’t. Neither had Rasputin, when his time finally came.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of listening to his instincts, Timothy reached into the bag and pulled out…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…a pornographic DVD case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three large ladies wearing cowboy hats and nothing else looked up at him from behind a bright orange clearance sticker. It was titled &lt;em&gt;Butt Fuck Sluts Go Totally Nuts&lt;/em&gt;. Interest piqued, Timothy opened the case, but it contained one orange Doritos thumbprint and nothing more. The spindle where the DVD itself should have been lay barren.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the bag was not empty. Timothy reached back in and pulled out a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under casual inspection the book seemed unremarkable. It was bound in brown leather, but not ostentatiously. It was not thick, nor was it thin. It had no smell at all, not the exciting, bland tang of a new book, nor the comforting, earthy musk of an old book. There was no title. No author. The book couldn’t have been plainer, but still there was something odd in the lines of its spine, the texture of its cover. The whole thing was offensive somehow, distressing like an Escher painting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy lifted the cover. There was no title page, no copyright information. Instead, the book started right in with a compact, margin-to-margin block of hand-written text in some strange language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Arabic?” Timothy mused aloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from a certain crawliness to the characters, the writing inside that book looked nothing at all like Arabic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy turned more pages. Illustrations were interspersed among the alien script. He stopped at a medieval woodcut of a skeleton playing a flute while a city—with all of its screaming inhabitants—burned in the background.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;The skeleton was Plague. Not infected fleas riding around on rats, but &lt;em&gt;Plague&lt;/em&gt;, the spiritual embodiment of death-by-buboes. Plague&amp;#39;s true name sounds like a soft, whistling fart, making it one of the few demons a person can summon rectally. Several have, much to history’s dismay.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy glanced over his shoulder, looking for the book’s owner, but the dining room was empty. With a slow little grin, like a child getting away with something, he slipped the book into his duffel bag and then, after a momentary consideration, took the empty DVD case as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out in the Denny’s parking lot, Timothy paused for a moment to look up at the sky. Low storm clouds threatened on the horizon, but Timothy didn’t make any association between the weather and the book. Instead, he got into his 1998 Geo Metro hatchback, a crumple-fendered, three-cylinder admission of failure, and tossed the duffel into the back seat.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;For the proper execution of an eventual Deus Ex Machina, it is important that you acknowledge now, safely in act I that Timothy does indeed own a car.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, as Timothy’s car reluctantly started and he puttered out of the parking lot, we’ll step out of the narrative for a moment and discuss the book, lying innocently enough next to the pornographic DVD case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing to know is that despite its appearance, the book wasn’t  a book at all. Not really. It was only a book in the way that an anglerfish’s lure is a cheerful little light glowing in the darkness. What Timothy had found in that booth was actually the chosen projection of a knotted inversion, an irreducible particle, a fundamental describer of reality and a manifestation of the Dark Lord’s will made material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among many other things, its pages contained the true names of a thousand denizens, creatures of the pit both mighty and meek. That alone didn’t mean much, as we’ve already discussed, but, unlike an ordinary book, it did not record information, it &lt;em&gt;defined&lt;/em&gt; information. The true names were true because they were written on the book’s pages. Worse still, the book possessed a sort of awareness and if it chose, it could whisper the correct pronunciations of those true names into the unsuspecting ear of whoever beheld its pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That so-called book was one of the most dangerous objects to be found anywhere, on any plane, high or low. On the eve of Armageddon, the Antichrist would read from its pages to bring forth the Horsemen and the end of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy Martin was not the ideal steward for such an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A Demon Appears&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Timothy walked into his small apartment, he found his roommates sitting on the couch, playing video games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey dude,” one of them said. His name was Sling, or so he called himself, mostly out of embarrassment that he wasn’t smart enough to bear the proud, nebbish name Herbert Richard Tower-Singleton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, hey,” the other said. This was Chris, who, unlike Timothy and Sling, occasionally had had a girlfriend. Most of his success in this regard could be attributed to two things: he had long, stringy rockstar hair and he could play &lt;em&gt;Rivers of Babylon&lt;/em&gt; on the guitar well enough to maintain the illusion his hair projected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Guys, damnit,” Timothy said, by way of greeting. “I asked you to clean up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apartment looked like a consignment shop carpeted sporadically in pizza boxes. What few decorations they possessed tended towards posters of girls in short-shorts twined around gigantic beer bottles.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;Girls who would likely marry into money or divorce out of second-hand gonorrhea, but never spare a glance for the roommates.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’ll get to it, man,” Sling said. Except to microwave a Hot Pocket and take a single, lengthy piss, Sling had not left the couch for going on six hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Come on. At least pick up these pizza boxes,” Timothy whined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure, sure,” Chris said, without looking away from the television.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whatever,” Timothy muttered and made his way towards his room at the very back of the apartment. He set the duffel bag, containing the book and the pornographic DVD case, on his desk and began to undress for a shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exactly two minutes and forty-nine seconds later, Timothy sprinted through the living room stark naked and screaming like a veal-calf on the last day of its incarceration. Riding on top of his head was a small, pitch-black bucket imp clutching its bucket with one hand and Timothy’s hair with the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, we pause for a moment. What is a bucket imp and how did one come to be riding Timothy like a grandstanding rodeo cowboy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer that, you need to understand that Hell is a liquid-filled place. There are literal lakes of bile, of shit, of brimstone, magma, sulfur, tears and boreworm semen. All of that goop occasionally needs to be moved from one place to another and all that moving falls to brigades of bucket imps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The imps are only six inches tall on average and humanoid in shape, though they possess a tail and a pair of oversized horns, relative to their tiny bodies. Each one comes equipped with a little bucket that they use to carry around the aforementioned fluids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, poor Timothy hadn’t expected to summon a demon.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;Technically, bucket imps aren’t really even demons; they’re stitched together from the remnants of damned souls, though those souls are so processed and modified that bucket imps are made of sinners the way a wiffleball is made of an apatosaurus. Pedantry aside, to the layman a bucket imp looks, acts and smells like a real demon, only on a small scale. They are, like everything else in Hell, more than a little ornery. It takes a full squad of whip damei to motivate one brigade of bucket imps and a full dozen gate lords (who aren’t really lords, but merely middle-management) to oversee one squad of bucket imps, all to perform a job that humans can accomplish with a sump pump.&lt;/span&gt; He had merely taken off his clothes for a shower, stopped by the book on his way into the bathroom and flipped through a few pages until he came upon a woodcut of a creature with the head of a turtle, the torso of a woman, crab legs and a pair of bat wings stomping on screaming human forms.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;The aforementioned Cik&amp;#39;dasra&amp;#39; Diq&amp;#39; Drisgz&amp;uuml;gatizzyrchs’ Ahrhch’ &amp;Ograve;ehp &amp;#39;Caxxcuxst doing what she does best.&lt;/span&gt; Slightly aroused by the sight of breasts, even if attached to a murderous crab-monster, Timothy touched the woodcut of the ever-stomping Cik&amp;#39;dasra&amp;#39; Diq&amp;#39; Drisgz&amp;uuml;gatizzyrchs’ Ahrhch’ &amp;Ograve;ehp &amp;#39;Caxxcuxst and then, fatefully, let his finger slide over onto a block of text in the next column.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“********” Timothy said softly, surprised by how good it felt to say those strange syllables, how perfectly they formed up in his mind, how dexterous his tongue felt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the last sigh of air had passed Timothy’s lips, the bucket imp appeared in front of him with a small &lt;em&gt;pop&lt;/em&gt; noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The imp and the naked man-boy stared at each other for a moment. Then the imp lunged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now you’re all caught up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Cook Vs. Janitor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy’s terrified sprint through the apartment ended abruptly when a pizza box slipped out from under his heel, sending him careening into the kitchenette, where he landed flat on his back.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;After his outburst over the pizza boxes, you might assume Timothy was a fastidious housekeeper, but he wasn’t. He merely disliked the square, grease-stained shapes of the pizza boxes. They reminded him of manta rays, those strange, flat fish often found in the petting pool at aquariums. Manta rays in turn reminded him of inflatable mattresses, which brought back memories of bed-wetting. Well not go further down this particular rabbit hole.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bucket imp detached itself well before Timothy’s crash and remained in the air above him, bobbing gently like a balloon on a string.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sling and Chris stared at the imp floating above Timothy with the all the intensity of two drowsy hedgehogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The fuck?” Chris muttered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get the book!” Timothy hollered. His extensive education in the supposed dark arts&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;Cook, M., &amp;amp; Collins, A. (2012). Dungeons &amp;amp; dragons: Dungeon master&amp;#39;s guide, core rulebook II, v5. Renton, WA: Wizards of the Coast.&lt;/span&gt; had taught him nothing of any use whatsoever in this particular situation, save one universal truth of demonology: far more important than the ritual to bring forth a demon is the ritual to put it away again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What is that?” Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get the boooooooook,” Timothy wailed. He was trying to stand up, but every time he made a move, the bucket imp snarled and lunged horns-first, which caused Timothy to fall back and flail his limbs like an infant on a changing table. His antics made the imp giggle, which was a horrible, nerves-combed-with-needles sort of sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris peeled himself off the couch and took a few steps towards the imp, holding out a hand like he was approaching a strange dog. The imp hurled its little bucket, hitting the curious hairbag directly on the snout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Owww, shit,” Chris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The imp zoomed down to catch the bucket on the rebound and then launched a second attack, this time striking Chris on the forehead. Again, the imp neatly retrieved its projectile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Get the book!” Timothy screamed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What book, dude?” Sling said. Now he was off the couch and making short lunges in various directions, only lacking something to lunge at or away from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris grabbed the first object he could lay hands on and took a swing at the bucket imp. That object turned out to be a wok lid sitting on the counter and it hit the imp with a musical &lt;em&gt;bong&lt;/em&gt;. The creature bounced against the wall and fell momentarily to the floor. The roomates gathered around, peering down at the it, but before the scene could even build any dramatic tension, the imp righted itself and lunged at Chris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bucket clanged against wok lid, filling the apartment with an unholy din. The other two housemates took up battle as well, Sling armed with a cushion from the couch and Timothy slap-fighting fearsomely, which looked something like a starveling chicken trying to escape a washing machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Trap it in the bathroom,” Timothy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through bulk and adrenal-induced berserkerism, the boys managed to push the imp down the hallway. It bobbed and darted in front of them, never touching the ground, lashing its tail like an angry cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy managed to throw open the bathroom door. With a roar, Sling batted it past the entryway with the wok lid. Chris threw the pillow and, in the instant the little creature dodged back out of the way, Timothy slammed the door, sealing it inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imp now locked in the bathroom, the roommates took a moment to regain their breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, Tim?” Sling said, panting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What the fuck is that thing?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A demon,” Timothy panted, leaning against the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, it isn’t,” Chris said. “There is no such—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The imp threw its bucket against the other side of the door with a solid &lt;em&gt;thunk&lt;/em&gt;. Chris, primed to say more, closed his mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, Tim?” Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why are you naked?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy gazed down upon his nudity. Than another bang from the other side of the door startled him out of his cock-reverie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We gotta get that book,&amp;quot; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The neophyte summoner shambled off at a half run, his pale, flabby-yet-scrawny buttocks jiggling.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;Everyone in Hell is naked, all of the time. This might sound like fun, but the great majority of humanity looks awful naked and even beautiful people aren’t particularly sexy while being flayed alive. Or boiled, buried, eaten, set on fire, etc. Heaven is a different story: no one is ever naked and under their robes angels are as neuter as Ken dolls. They play a lot of bingo in heaven. A lot. Hell sucks by design. Heaven sucks by demographics.&lt;/span&gt; When he returned, he was hopping into the pants he had worn at work all day while trying to flip through the book at the same time. This operation failed when he slipped on another pizza box, leaving him sprawled on the floor, somehow hogtied by his black work slacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I told you to pick up those boxes,” Timothy nearly sobbed, regaining his footing and, at long, long last, managing to shove his genitals back into his pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s with the book?” Chris demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The thing in there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a demon. I summoned it. It’s one of these.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He he flipped past Cik&amp;#39;dasra&amp;#39; Diq&amp;#39; Drisgz&amp;uuml;gatizzyrchs’ Ahrhch’ &amp;Ograve;ehp &amp;#39;Caxxcuxst to the next page, where there was a little picture of a bucket imp. He showed it to Chris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Huh,” Chris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We need to send it back,” Timothy said. He started leafing through pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still locked in the bathroom, the imp threw its bucket against the door in a quick, triple beat. &lt;em&gt;Toktoktok&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s a demon in the bathroom?” Sling said, celebrating Christmas on Boxing Day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Here,” Timothy said pointing to a passage. “This is its name. I can say that and then command it to return to its…uhh…wherever it came from. I think.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Dude, there is no way that thing is a—&amp;quot; Chris said, but he was cut off when Timothy’s convincing rebuttal hurled its bucket against the door again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let me see that,” Chris said instead, snatching the book. “These aren’t even letters.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A demon. That’s kinda cool,” Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You have to trust me,” Timothy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, I don’t,” Chris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I summoned it. I can unsummon it,” Timothy said with some conviction.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;This hilariously untrue statement is very often a summoner’s last.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Toktoktok&lt;/em&gt;, the imp interjected with its bucket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I need you to open the door and push it back long enough for me to say the words,” Timothy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Okay. Fuck it,” Chris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Alright,” Timothy said, “one, two, three!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris took a deep breath and then, with a shout, he pushed the door open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Situation Gets Worse&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The imp was hovering over the toilet, bailing water out of the bowl and onto the floor. Lost in its familiar task, the little shadow was startled by the door opening. There was a momentary pause. The imp blinked its yellow eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Splash&lt;/em&gt;, said the bucket, tipping about about a quarter of a cup of water onto the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“********,” Timothy intoned, book open in one hand, other arm raised theatrically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another bucket imp promptly appeared just behind his left ear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy shrieked and batted at the newcomer with the book. The imp hissed and flitted away but Timothy, with help from Chris, managed to push this new visitor into the bathroom with the first imp. Unfortunately, somewhere in the melee, Tim actually threw the book at the imp and then Chris slammed the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“See? I told you I can summon them,” Timothy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Great job, man. Really great job,” Chris said, back against the door. On the other side, the imps hammered for a while and then things went quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You threw the book at them,” Sling chuckled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What are they doing in there?” Chris said, pressing his ear to the door. “I can hear them. Are they talking?”&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;They were. An exact translation of this conversation would be tedious; imps have seventy-two words to describe various pitchfork impalings, yet they resort to “big sky eye fire” to describe sunlight and “toilet” was simply beyond their experience. Mostly, they stuck to asinine elevator topics, observational stuff like “there sure isn’t very much magma up here.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We need to call the cops,” Sling said, “for real.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,” Timothy said, “The police are highly trained to handle demons. Like they’d even believe us. No. We’re on our own.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;”We’re on our own” could be the demon summoner&amp;#39;s union credo if they had a union, which they do not. Because they all hate each other.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, shut up,” Chris told him. “Sling, go call the cops.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sling&amp;#39;s phone was lost somewhere out in the wilds of the couch cushions, but he eventually returned, already on the line with the police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. Something in the bathroom. I don&amp;#39;t know what. Uh huh. Maybe uhh…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sling looked at Chris for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A bat,” Chris mouthed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, maybe it’s a bat,” Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several little buckets clattered against the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bats,” Sling amended. “There’s a few of them now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Rabies, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A longer pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, the Barton Apartment building. Apartment thirty six.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, it is an emergency. Animal control? Come on, that’s…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sling started screaming into the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Aaaaahh, shit, they got out, they’re biting me! Oh shit, oh shiiiiittt. Aaaahh! Help! There’s so much blood!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sling ended the call and smiled at the roommates with a satisfied stoner squint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well?” Timothy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They didn’t want to come,” Sling said, “but they probably will.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Those things are talking in there,” Chris said, pressing an ear to the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m gonna go get a shirt, Timothy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The police, frequent visitors at the Barton Apartments, though usually for noise violations instead of summonings gone astray, appeared about half an hour later. While they waited, Timothy put on a shirt, but otherwise the roommates kept their ears to the door. The imps on the other side had gone ominously quiet. When the unmistakable cop-knock finally came,  Sling let them in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you’ve got some kind of animal problem?” the first officer—a black guy—said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. They’re in the bathroom,” Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Any of you been doing a little smoke?” the second cop—a white guy—said, eying the bong prominently displayed on the coffee table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No?” Sling said, really sticking the landing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bats in the bathroom, huh?” the white cop said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s right, officer,” Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Been seeing any other nasty critters around? Babies crawling around on the ceiling? Bugs under your skin, maybe?” the white cop said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Christ, Rick,” the black officer said, “Why not ask them if they’re hopped up on goofballs?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Arrest us later,” Chris said. “Just come see whats in the bathroom first.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh yeah. That’s some kind of line,” the black officer said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policemen made their way down the hall and took up position outside the bathroom, shooing the housemates out of the way. The white officer put his ear to the door, then shrugged. The black officer had a listen too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I hear something. A popping sound?” the black officer said. He turned to the roommates. “What else you three want to tell us before I open this door?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s not bats,” Timothy said. “It’s a pair of demons I summoned.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One cannot know whether Timothy told the officers the truth out of civic responsibility or an urge to boast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh. Is that all?” the black officer said and opened the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three thousand, three hundred, thirty two bucket imps burst through the doorway in a rush of shadow and glowing, yellow eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Carnage, Flight&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a little-known fact that demons can summon other demons and do so frequently. The whole power structure of Hell depends on it. Satan summons his Lords, his Lords summon lieutenants, the lieutenants summon their overseers, the overseers summon their assorted worker-imps and, bob’s-yer-uncle, the Center for Infernal Justice gets a new Auto-Cannibalism Annex. Bucket imps, residing as they do at the very base of Hell’s phone tree, have very limited authority, but they are capable of summoning one specific denizen: each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under ordinary circumstances, though, imps cannot summon anything at all on the mortal plane. Under ordinary circumstances, imps should never be &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; the mortal plane. These were not ordinary circumstances though. With the book in play, the imps were capable of summoning almost anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phrases like “malevolent cloud” or “wicked horde” are tempting here, but bucket imps don’t merit such grandiosity. At best, they were a flock. Think seagulls. Similar to seagulls making a mass-takeoff down the beach, it was impossible to pick any one individual imp from the collective. Shrieking and giggling like schoolgirls at a slumber party, the little flock rolled out into the hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imps tangled in hair. They stole the white cop’s hat. More crawled under shirts while the general majority amused themselves with non-specific bucket-whackings. The humans careened off each other and the walls, trying to escape in five different directions down a hallway that really only offered two. Somewhere in the melee, Timothy found himself face-down on the bathroom floor. There, he saw more than a dozen imps still bailing water out of the toilet, because some imps just have a stronger work ethic than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the cops—it was impossible to say which, buried as they were in imps—started firing his gun, which did a fantastic job of killing the roommates damage deposit but not much else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swatting frantically, the roommates managed to fall back into the living room. More gunfire emerged from the hallway. The police retreated to Timothy’s bedroom and there they died. The roommates didn’t see exactly what happened, but the gunfire turned to shouts and then screams and then the screams cut off abruptly, as if a signal had been given. The imps returned to the hallway in a lazy, cheerful cloud. Many carried buckets of blood, full to sloshing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The roommates ran. Out of the apartment. Into the hallway. Panting, sobbing, groping along the walls like blind men. They tried to close the door, but imps piled into the gap and, working together, they heaved it back open, squeaking their ridiculous little battle cries as they took up pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Down the stairs, the flock just behind them, until they burst out the fire door and into the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dusk was giving way to night and a light drizzle was falling. The roommates ran across the parking lot—past Timothy’s Metro—to the edge of a park that abutted the apartment complex. The imps followed them, but then lost interest when they found themselves in a world where liquid fell from the sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gasping, the roommates watched the imps as they milled about, their little lantern eyes turned upwards in amazement. The door leading back into the apartment had never really closed under the flow of exiting imps, but now it bulged wide as a particularly large knot of the little shadows pushed free. This group had something, a brownish something, held aloft between many tiny claws and across a dozen wee backs. It was the book. With its help, one of the imps was busy summoning his friends in bulk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We gotta do something,” Sling said, shifting his weight from foot to foot like he had to urinate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, we do,” Timothy said, with unusual steel in his voice. “And I know what.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Run?” Chris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy shook his head. He was not wearing shoes or a jacket, but he was wearing his work pants and so he had the keys to his car in the front right pocket and his cell phone in the other.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;A fact prudently mentioned and subtlety emphasized earlier. Deus Ex Machina is a delicate dance of forethought.&lt;/span&gt; He pulled the keys out and tossed them thoughtfully from hand to hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What are you doing?” Chris snapped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;They like water, don&amp;#39;t they?&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Sure?&amp;quot; Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Call the police again. Tell them to bring the National Guard,” Timothy said. He handed his cell phone to Sling. “And oh, take a video.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. Okay,” Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What are you doing?” Chris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m going to stall them.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t exactly a declaration of war, but it was still pretty good, considering the source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Heroic Plan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from a few disinterested whacks, the imps mostly ignored Timothy as he crossed the parking lot. He climbed into the Metro and turned the key. Unfortunately, the Metro had an addled prima donna of a starter that didn’t like humidity. Now, it made a terrible screech, but that was all. He tried again and got the same screech. Timothy considered the situation. He fastened his seatbelt, tried the car again. Nothing. He pounded on the steering wheel and screamed. The other two eventually strolled over, Sling still recording. Chris tapped on the window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy took a breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He rolled the window down a crack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I need a push,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why?” Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To get the car started. Get it rolling and I’ll pop start it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Metro weighed about as much as a couch, so Sling and Chris were able to shove the little car out of the space and get it headed off generally in the direction of the street. Timothy waited until the Metro had reached a jogging speed and then he popped the clutch. The car jerked, lagged, nearly stopped and then puttered awake. Without pause to reflect on his own considerable cowardice, Timothy and put the pedal to the novelty anime-themed floor mat and the Metro hustled across the lot, across the street, up onto the opposite sidewalk and directly into a fire hydrant, which promptly exploded into a fountain of irresistible, free-running water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The imps, formerly wandering off to every point of the compass, about-faced and charged back to the water gushing from the broken hydrant and began bailing with glee. Timothy, dazed but unharmed, got out of the car and promptly tripped over a knot of imps, gashing his forehead on the curb. Stumbling upright, he managed the journey across the street without further incident. By then, the imps had landed on the Metro en masse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That was sweet, man,” Sling yelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed. As a delaying tactic, Timothy’s plan seemed sound. Unfortunately, there was much he didn’t understand about imp psychology and their instinct to swarm. Prior to the eruption of the fire hydrant, the imp with the book was idly summoning its pals so they could have a look at the mortal plane. Now that something worth bailing had appeared, the imp considered itself back on the clock and, empowered by the book, it chanted and imps poured forth into the moral realm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s bad,” Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yup,” Chris agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three thousand, a full legion. Two legions. Like Alabama ants in a drought, the imps swarmed the hydrant, nearly blacking it out with their tiny, squirming bodies. Within a minute, perhaps less, some of the imps had chased the water back into the pipes that delivered it while others ran down every free drop in the gutters while further hordes bailed what had already been bailed. They bailed and bailed, with no direction, but unlimited energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sirens wailed in the far-off distance, but by the time the police arrived, the street might be filled with imps from gutters to stratosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Hero Does Battle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy, owner of a Monster Manual allegedly signed by Gygax, knight of Halo, occasional defender of his own dignity and reluctant champion of not one single thing, surveyed the scene. All up and down the street, people stood in their doorways or peered out of windows. His car had nearly vanished under the imp heap—just its round ass stuck out of the pile—and the horde continued to multiply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a steadying breath, Timothy stepped off the curb. He took another step. He stripped off his t-shirt and wound it into a rope between his fists. He turned to Chris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Lighter,” he growled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris underhanded his Zippo and Timothy caught it without ever taking his gaze off the pile of imps. Thus armed, he walked across the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, the imps ignored him. He walked right up to the car and even brushed a few of the imps away from the gas-input hole cover.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;It’s strange that Americans, a people both blessed with a nuanced language and possessing an Oedipal love of their motor vehicles, don’t have a special word to describe this area of a car.&lt;/span&gt; Still unmolested, he unscrewed the cap, stuck a good length of his twisted-up shirt into the hole and then, under a continuing barrage of indifference from the imps, he painstakingly set the shirt on fire. It took a while, but eventually the flame caught and began to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy sprinted back to the park and his waiting friends, expecting at any moment to feel an insistent push at his back followed by a wave of heat. Instead, he arrived at the curb out of breath and the three of them turned to watch the Metro’s continued non-explosion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Huh,” Chris said, while Sling recorded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shirt flared yellow for a moment and then seemed to go out. A fresh wave of imps arrived, shifting the geometry of the pile, and the car vanished entirely under the mass of limbs and buckets. The boys watched for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Goddamnit,” Timothy panted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Were you trying to blow up your car?” Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Metro exploded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any self-respecting revolutionary will tell you that the wick on improvised explosives—Molotov cocktails, Geo Metros—ought to be soaked in something combustible before use. T-shirts don’t burn very well on their own. That Timothy’s idiotic plan worked at all was largely due to an equal idiocy working in the opposite direction, as is almost always the case.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;The only person dumber than Odysseus was the Trojan who thought that horse would make a good conversation piece.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That necessary idiocy was provided by one of the imps, who, frustrated by its inability to reach the water under its many, many friends, detected some sort of liquid down at the end of a tight, narrow pipe. So the imp wriggled into the hole, down past some sort of smoldering material that it found reassuringly Hell-like, then splashed into a dark little cave that that smelled rather cheerfully nostalgic. Pleased, the imp began bailing, as is the wont of its kind. As it bailed, a few, fine droplets of gasoline went up the pipe, where they met the last, fading ember of Timothy’s charred t-shirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the little car was busy doing exciting exothermic things with gasoline, thousands of flaming imps went on unexpected journeys into the sky and the resulting fireball blinded the roommates. Up and down the block, lookieloos started screaming while Sling went right on recording.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the imps, the explosion was interesting, but completely harmless as it takes a lot more than the contents of one Geo Metro’s stomach to hurt a denizen. In Hell it is considered a little rude to explode someone without cause though, so the flock drew itself back together and then whirled up into an agitated mass, before spilling across the street in a rippling tide. The boys—and everyone else in the vicinity—would have died then, if another demon not suddenly appeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Demon Ex Machina&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was called Tiramok, and she was a lieutenant of Hell. She stood taller as the walls of Babylon, her horns were broad as a river in flood and her claws had could impale four men standing front to back. A whispered from her lips could poison, corrupt and kill. Whole companies of angels scattered at the sight of her on the horizon. She was aftermath. She was the carrion crow. She was the battle lost. Her name, her true name, was the sound of rain on the ashes of a village swept bare by raiders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, in this case, in the presence of the Book, her name was perfectly pronounced by hydrant water sizzling against the hot roof of a recently-exploded Geo Metro.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;When one commits to a Deus Ex Machina, its best to &lt;em&gt;commit&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tirarmok surveyed the scene with her ghastly, ghostlamp eyes and a seismic growl issued up from her throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Whodares&lt;/em&gt;?” she said in rather posh demonic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then she saw the imps. And the book. And the humans standing around with expressions on their faces that revealed a complete lack of understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Oh, damnit&lt;/em&gt;,” the demon muttered, with significantly less menace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bucket imps threw themselves prostrate at her cloven feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tirarmok sighed. Two bursts of flame erupted from her nose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**********, she shouted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another demon appeared at her side. This second demon was quite menacing, but only about the size of a human, with the head of a pig, the torso of an ant and the legs of a male ballerina. It carried a long whip coiled over its shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Yes, master?&lt;/em&gt;” the new demon hissed, also in demonic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tirarmok pointed at the worshipful pile of imps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Ha!&lt;/em&gt;,” the new demon said, “&lt;em&gt;How’d they get up here?&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tirarmok bent and picked up the book from where it lay near the Metro. She showed it to the other demon. It was unmarked from its adventures.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;We are  required at this point to admit that Timothy&amp;#39;s pornographic DVD, introduced conspicuously as a Chekhovian gun in act one, serves no further role in this narrative. Apologies for any anticipation you might have experienced waiting for its return.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Oh. That thing. Slippery, slippery. Likes to go wandering.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;He is going to be angry,&lt;/em&gt;” Tirarmok muttered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;It’s not your fault, is it? You’re not the thing’s keeper,&lt;/em&gt;” the other demon said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;It’s political.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Best get moving. By your leave?&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiramok nodded. The pig-ant-ballerina turned to the imps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Right, you lot. Hup to.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the crack of an infernal whip, the imps pulled themselves into a raged semblance of a parade rest. A moment later, they all vanished. Tirarmok stood with the book tweezered carefully between her claws and looked up and down the street. Cops were arriving on the scene with their lights flashing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Idiots,” Tirarmok muttered before she too vanished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Metro continued to burn. Official types began their own sort of swarming, setting up barricades and cordoning off the street. Almost unnoticed, the roommates stood in the parking lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What just happened?” Sling said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have no idea,” Chris said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timothy only smiled. He was a summoner now. Soon, the world would feel his wrath.&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;He wasn’t and it wouldn’t.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="content" /><summary type="html">Tim buys a book. Tim accidentally summons a demon. Hilarity, carnage, ensue.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Last Minute Truth</title><link href="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/10/08/a-last-minute-truth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Last Minute Truth" /><published>2015-10-08T16:48:16-06:00</published><updated>2015-10-08T16:48:16-06:00</updated><id>https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/10/08/a-last-minute-truth</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/10/08/a-last-minute-truth.html">&lt;h3&gt;Life With Joe&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace had the gun, a belly full of whiskey, and the moment his television program was over, he would kill himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program on the television was one of those soap operas about a hospital. On screen, noble doctors scrambled to save a girl on the operating table. There had been an accident. Eustace, snake-deaf and mostly disinterested, couldn’t keep pace with the show’s dialog, but that didn’t matter. Cutting someone open. Running around. Crying. Sneaking into the supply closet for a tryst. The doctors on TV inhabited a world filled with motion, whereas Eustace’s world—which was not the real world, but instead something called Lutheran Eldercare—stood silent and still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the far corner of the room, lying entombed in a state-issued hospital bed, Eustace’s roommate Joe groaned in his sleep and shifted restlessly. Eustace squinted over at the enshrouded form, waiting for the inevitable. Then it came. Joe farted, a low, wet flapper. Only time would tell if he had shit himself again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The doctor program went to commercial and Eustace reached surreptitiously under the recliner for the bottle of whiskey. The orderlies didn’t know about the booze and they surely didn’t know he had the gun, or they would have taken both away from him before he could say “God bless Betty Ford.” Keeping quiet. That was the secret here in the Eldercare. Keep quiet and they’ll be happy to ignore you forever. Joe, who &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; shit himself—and in grand fashion—was proof of that; he only complained rectally, and nobody ever bothered him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You stinking son of a bitch!” Eustace growled—nearly sobbed—as the fart started to stink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right after the show. Time to go. Way past time. Eustace glanced at the clock. Ten forty-five in the morning. Another fifteen minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The door to the outside hall stood open and Eustace wanted it that way, so nothing would muffle his final word, but an open door also required prudence. He got the remote and fumbled the television’s volume way down, listening for the squeak of orderly shoe on tile. Nothing. Satisfied, Eustace reached a shriveled paw into the recliner’s elasticized side-pouch, where the pistol waited. His fingers crawled across the hammer and the barrel and over the dimples of the cylinder. This wasn’t the way he would have chosen, but it would do. He pulled the pistol free and set it in his lap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a Colt Single Action Army, a Peacemaker, handed down from his grandfather to his father and finally to Eustace. It was an antique and probably valuable, but never once in all the decades since since inheriting the thing had Eustace considered selling it, not even during some hard, hard times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten till the hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace reached back into the recliner’s pouch for the ammo. The cardboard carton was old and frayed white around the corners, but the blunt rounds inside shone clean and brass-bright. He’d smuggled them into the Eldercare wrapped in a ball of his own boxer shorts. Would they still work? He thought they probably would. The Peacemaker itself wanted for oil, but still operated smoothly enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pulled the hammer back to half-cock and liked the sound. The gate came open smoothly and he thumbed in the first bullet with a shaking hand. He skipped the next chamber and fed four more rounds to the gun. Never give a Peacemaker the full six rounds. Five was enough. His daddy had taught him that. Eustace dropped the gun back onto his lap and resumed watching television.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe let fly again, a high, jaunty whistle that should have set the bastard’s bed sheets on fire. Eustace had long ago dubbed that particular cannonade “the brass band.” Better that than the subtler, but far nastier “angry crocodile.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Lord, look what he had been reduced to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After what seemed like a hell of a long time, the doctors finally saved the girl’s life and the credits came up. Staring fixedly at the television, Eustace groped around in his lap until he found the gun. It was heavier than it should be. His chicken arms shook from the effort of lifting it. A bank commercial came on, starring a goofy guy in a polo shirt who walked through a mountain meadow while yammering about home loans and free checking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace glared at the television, giving it the same look Joe got for farting. When he wanted to open his own repair shop, the bank had been happy to give him a loan. Real happy. But when things went sour, that goddamned bank had come and taken his house. He and Shirley moved into a rented trailer and he had to start working for that prick, Ernie, again. Life never did get back to right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here he was, stuck in this shit-befouled, pauper purgatory where the pills came every three hours and the television was the only living thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace pointed his pistol at the goofy fellow with the polo shirt and the free checking. He pulled the hammer back to full-cock and again he liked the authoritative click it made settling into place. He pulled the trigger. The Peacemaker&amp;#39;s hammer fell on the empty chamber Joe hadn&amp;#39;t loaded with a dry, businesslike snap and he grinned. When they came and took his house away from him, he had stood by docile as a mule and then he’d spent most of his life turning a wrench under someone else’s car for the price of a hamburger or two an hour. He’d done it for the kids, and for Shirley, and that’d been right and maybe he didn’t regret it, exactly, but Shirley was long dead, same deal with his youngest son, the only one of the three that had ever been worth a damn. The other two, both of them old men in their own rights, never called and never wrote and had left him in this place without so much as a fare-thee-well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did that leave? Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence the Peacemaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace glanced out the door. Still empty. The wall clock, hanging above some Christmas cards from Joe’s niece and nephew, said it was three minutes to eleven. It seemed important to go out on a nice, round eleven o’clock. Or noon. Did that matter? Noon would be intentional. Poetic. Right. High noon. A last gunfight in the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A man should use what freedom he’s allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thought came to Eustace from far off, as if someone had mailed it to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That bank commercial guy. Low rates. Stop on in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace sat, fiddling with the gun and waiting for his passing thought to assemble itself into a course of action. Once he had it, he sat a little longer, wondering at the simplicity of it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Get Up, Get Dressed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, he needed to pry himself out of the chair. He positioned each limb just so and then, after an assessment of leverage, weights and air resistance, he hoisted himself up, creakingly aware of his fragile hips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually Eustace attained a state of upright and shuffled over to the closet, stripping out of his robe as he went. Underneath, he was buck-assed naked, beyond a pair of socks and his slippers, but if that offended Joe, well, Joe shit himself. On the way across the room, Eustace happened to catch his reflection in the bathroom mirror. His body sagged where it hadn’t mummified. He could see his actual self under that mess though, handsome, with a dimpled chin and a pair of green eyes that used to have the leg-spreading voodoo. Or maybe what he saw was only the ghost of what he remembered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the closet, Eustace decided on his suit. He might as well make this a formal occasion. Starting with underwear, working ponderously, he got the suit on (worn only to funerals in recent years) and finished with a red bow tie Shirley said he looked natty in and natty was hunky-dory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dressed, Eustace put his robe back on and wrapped it tight. The orderlies expected their inmates to wear the proper uniform at all times. That Eustace had had his best wingtips on, not to mention a fine wool suit, didn’t matter a tittle, so long as he had the robe. On his way out the door, he grabbed a twenty dollar bill off of his dresser. It was the only money he had. The Eldercare received his government check directly, on the assumption he had become too addlebrained to pay the rent on his own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which he wasn’t. Addlebrained. At least he was pretty sure on that. Most of the marbles were still up in his marble box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had to move fast now; if he slowed down, this craziness might drain out of him and that would be a shame. He reached in under the robe and under the jacket of his suit and shoved the gun into the waistband of his pants. It was a stupid way to carry a loaded firearm around—unless he was aiming to blow his balls off—but stupid was the order of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armed and dressed, Eustace grabbed an envelope tacked to the bulletin board next to the door. Some MediCare thing his son wanted him to sign. Eustace didn’t know what the papers signified, nor did he care. What mattered is that it had the ungrateful bastard’s return address on the envelope. Eustace shoved the whole wad into his robe pocket and stepped out into the hallway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ricky—aka The Fat One—was at the orderly’s station, watching television and shoving Cheetos down his gaping, hippo mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Eustace passed by, Ricky grunted and waved. He didn’t stand up, but he did take his feet off the desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace nodded, keeping his head down. He wanted to appear good and zombie-like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Going for a walk there, buddy?” Ricky said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure,” Eustace mumbled, “Stretch my legs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t get into any trouble.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ricky went back to the television and Eustace continued his hobble down the hallway. Upon opening the front door (Mother Mary, how did something so simple as opening a door get to be so hard?) and stepping out into the late November sunshine, Eustace was struck with that prisoner’s awe at the size of the outside world. His life was spent in hibernation; whole days passed without him moving any further than the bathroom. Now cars zoomed past every-which-way and even the wind struck him as a trifle intimidating. A helicopter flew overhead. Eustace shivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he struggled out of his robe and dropped the filthy old thing on the ground like a shed skin. Immediately, he felt better. He adjusted his lapels and felt better still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The corner store, Eustace’s first destination, was a few blocks up from the Eldercare. It was quite a walk, but he managed, even doffing an imaginary hat to a pretty girl. She smiled at him and waved, laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bell above the door jangled as Eustace maneuvered into the corner store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good morning,” the wrinkled, sun-dried woman at the counter said, looking at Eustace’s improbable formal wear with one eyebrow cocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mornin!” Eustace said, beaming. He placed the twenty dollar bill on the counter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What can I do for you?” the woman said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Smokes,” Eustace barked, scanning the shelves myopically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Smokes huh? What kind?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace checked his memory. He’d had a brand once, before he’d stopped smoking in…whenever he’d stopped smoking, which had been a long time ago. Sunbeam or Dancer or…hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Luckies,” he said. They weren’t his brand, but they should have been. Brand that killed the Nazis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Lucky Strike?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Those are them,” Eustace agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clerk had to look around for a while, but she finally found a pack high up on the shelf and set it on the counter. It was covered in a light robe of dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Got some matches?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think so. Somewhere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gimmie a bag, too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clerk produced a tiny plastic bag that was just barely big enough for the deck of smokes. Eustace shook his head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bigger bag. Biggest you got.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How is this?” she said, holding up a full-sized paper grocery bag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bingo!” Eustace said, pulling his lips back from a picket of yellowed, but mostly present, teeth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace picked up the cigarettes and dropped them into the pocket of his jacket along with the matches, then took the empty bag and tucked it under his arm. The clerk raised her eyebrow again, but made change without comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You have a good day,” Eustace said, shuffling to the door. The  woman watched him go and gently closed the drawer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A Trip To The Mercury&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a bus stop directly across from the corner store. Eustace hobbled over to the shelter and had himself a seat on the bench. After making sure no one could see him, he pulled the pistol out of the waistband of his pants. He considered the gun for a moment, before dropping it into the paper bag. He folded the bag over twice, so it made a tidy little package, and tucked it under his arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He squinted up at the bus schedule, realized he couldn’t read it, further realized he didn’t know what time it was. Didn’t matter. A bus would come along and he would hop aboard. While he waited, he peeled the wrapper off his Luckies and pulled one of the cigarettes out, relishing the good smell of tobacco. He’d quit for Shirley, after the lung cancer had got its crab legs deep into her. Solidarity and soforth. Made her happy and afterwords he’d forgotten to take the habit back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace stuck the Lucky into the corner of his mouth. It took him three tries to strike a match—his hands had a hard time with fine tasks—but the first, trembling inhalation made the effort worthwhile. Like coming home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He leaned back and watched a pair of sparrows bicker in a winter-bare bush nearby. Scummy gray snow from the storm a few days back lined the gutters, and the sun, while warm against his face, had that peculiar winter hardness to it. He took another long drag, and then blew out. Then he coughed for a good while and his head felt swimmy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a bus rolled up, Eustace got on. The driver told him to lose the cigarette, which he did, and then Eustace took out his envelope and asked the man how to find the address written thereon. The driver gave him a long explanation, but Eustace didn’t bother paying attention. All that mattered was that he was headed in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two hours and three transfers later, Eustace stepped off a different bus in an unfamiliar neighborhood. Big, new houses squatted on tiny lots like a row of bulldogs all shitting on napkins. His useless elder son was living the American dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace pulled the envelope out of his pocket, and started walking. At each house along the street, he shuffled up, peered at the address until it came into reasonable focus, checked the envelope again and then moved on. It took him half an hour to traverse the three blocks between the bus stop and the porch of what he hoped was Useless Son’s house. Useless Son as opposed to Drunken Son or Dead Son.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By then, Eustace was literally panting, his tongue poking over his lower lip like a dried-up tuber. He double-double-checked the envelope then looked at the numbers by the house’s door. It was a definite match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace celebrated by sitting on the front step. It was about one in the afternoon, maybe two. Or three. Afternoon, anyway. He looked up and down the street, wondering at the complete and total stillness. Not so much as a housecat. No sign of life from inside either. Where were Useless Son and the Skinny Harpy? Eustace didn’t know. Useless Son was in the far reaches of sixty by now, and retired, so the little shit didn’t have anywhere in particular to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe he was at the doctor. That gave Eustace a thrill. Maybe Useless Son was discovering that old happened to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe they were inside, peeking out through the blinds while the Harpy called the Eldercare to come collect him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Eustace’s heart had resumed its usual wheezing throb and his tongue fit into his mouth again, he stood and made his way towards the garage. It had two big doors, one for each of the two cars it could hold. Those doors would be hopeless. Even if they didn’t have openers, they’d be too heavy for him to lift. But the garage had a side door, for people, not cars, around the corner. That door was locked. Eustace jiggled the handle, kicked it and even threw a shoulder against the door, trying to batter it down with his scarecrow bulk, but nothing happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ok. We’ll see. We’ll see,” Eustace said to the door, as he unfolded the paper bag from around the Peacemaker. Squinting and turning his face to the side, as if he were afraid it would slap him, Eustace pointed the gun just to the right of the doorknob and slowly squeezed the trigger. A brisk explosion, much louder than Eustace had expected, rolled up and down the street. The recoil staggered him back ten feet, but a hole, roughly the size and shape of a soup can, appeared in the door where the latch had formerly met frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dogs all around the neighborhood raised an alarm. With the pistol’s kick still clanging his bones together like church bells, Eustace took a quick look at the streets—no cops, at least not yet—and tried the door. This time it swung politely open. Chuckling, Eustace stepped into the garage and laid eyes on his old girl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was a 1950 Mercury Monterrey, yard upon yard of Detroit steel. Not exactly in great shape—faded paint and a hardtop with only a few remaining scraps of vinyl—but doing no worse than Eustace himself. Purchased used sometime in his later thirties, the car was what they would call a mid-life crisis purchase—or, one-third-of-life crisis, considering Eustace’s collection of years. He’d driven her up until…right around the time the red-faced President (Carter?) got his dick sucked by that fat…actress?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, rather than sell her, Eustace had grudgingly given the Merc over to Useless Son. Every time Useless Son showed up at the Eldercare (which was almost never), Eustace pestered him about the Merc. Keep her in a garage and be sure to give her some exercise now and again. Change the plugs, willya?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, yeah, of course, pops,” Useless Son would say, “I’m taking care of it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace half-believed the little fart had gone and sold his girl, but here she was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace ran a hand along the Merc’s curved, downward-sloping flank, taking in her scabrous interior and missing chrome. He walked around back and checked the plates. Licensed and everything, with some of those fancy classic car tags. Now it was only a matter of keys. Eustace bowed stiffly at the waist, like an English butler, and, propping himself carefully against the car’s black hide, felt around under the front wheel well, searching for the nifty magnetic hide-a-key key box he’d secreted away all those years ago. After a little groping, he found it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ha!” Eustace cackled, performing a shuffling two-step on the dusty concrete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That left only one minor detail: escape. The garage came equipped with a door-opener, he could see that, but its operation escaped him. It didn’t matter; a more direct solution presented itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gun went back into paper sack. Paper sack went into car, on the passenger side of the bench seat. Then Eustace performed the complicated ritual of folding his superannuated body into a sitting position behind the Merc’s wheel. From there, he had to stop and take stock. A long time ago, his body had been wired to perform all the actions required to start a car and get it moving, but now each step required conscious thought. Key went into ignition. One foot on the clutch, one on the gas, put her in reverse. Turn the key. On his first attempt, the car turned over, caught, but then his foot slipped off the clutch and the Merc lurched a few inches before dying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Damn,” Eustace muttered. He slapped the steering wheel and tried again. This time he got the Merc started and then let her sit for a minute, listening to the engine. A little rough, but who knew how old the gas was? That led him to another important question: how much gas? He bent over the wheel and peered at the gauge, which stood at under an eighth of a tank. He tapped the glass over the needle with a thick fingernail, but the gauge stayed put.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace grunted and revved the engine. Old or not, a Merc straight-six spoke with authority. With his face peeled back into a shit-eating grin, Eustace craned his head around, popped the clutch and slammed his foot down on the gas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The engine roared and the Merc launched backwards, punching through the garage door like a linebacker through the paper banner at a homecoming game. Jagged spikes of wood blew out all across Useless Son’s driveway as the Merc hurtled towards the street. Eustace screamed and jabbed his foot down on the brake. The car squealed. Stalled. Panting, but still wearing that grin, he sat and looked at the hole he’d left in Useless Son’s garage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would take more than a little plywood to patch that action up. Eustace poked his head out the window and looked back for damage on the Merc. A few scrapes, but nothing serious. The ruckus set all the neighborhood hounds off again, but there was still no activity on the street. No mothers poking their heads out of their doors, no children pointing. Eustace supposed all the mothers were at work, just like the fathers, and their kids would be at school or in cold-storage somewhere, waiting for someone to bail them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace restarted the Merc and tried easing her into motion, but working the clutch woke the arthritis in his hip and knee. It took him three more stalls to maneuver the car to the end of the driveway. By then he was starting to get the hang of driving again, never mind the red throb rolling up and down his left leg. The Merc pulled out onto the street smoothly enough. From there, he made three right turns at random, passing more of those identical bulldog houses. They said he was too old to drive, and they were right; his cataracts demoted everything at any sort of  a distance—stop signs, trees and cars parked on the curbs—to fuzzy shadows, identifiable only by color. Even so, Eustace felt great. He couldn’t stop smiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But he needed a rest. After all that walking and sitting, his joints had unionized, led by his clutch-working knee, and were singing a high note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintaining a wobbly fifteen, Eustace piloted the Merc down another six blocks, until he came to a neighborhood park. The Merc’s breaks moaned in protest as it came to a stop by the curb, in a patch of sun that beat nicely against the roof. Just a few minutes would do him up nicely. He swung his legs around and set them on the bench seat, the brown-bagged Peacemaker between his thighs. Stretched out, with his head resting on his suit coat, Eustace lit another Lucky and sighed out a streamer of smoke, watching the play of sun against bare branch in the tree above. Within seconds, he was asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he slept, he dreamed. Of Shirley, his wife. Of a Mexican whore who had gotten him drunk, given him a tepid hand job and then stolen his wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artifice and not even that much of a pleasure, guilty or otherwise. But there’d been more than just the one, hadn’t there? Across the border into Juarez. He’d put his wallet in his front pocket and he’d gone back. Wiggling, giggling, paid for. Cheap as a dinner out and not one ever told him that he shouldn’t or that he should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow all of that dissolved into a new scene: Shirley and the whore sitting on a couch and talking about him, like he wasn’t there. What if it doesn&amp;#39;t work out? Shirley asked, How will he feed his children? The whore shook her head, her fat, powdered jowls wagging their disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace woke up slowly and when his eyes finally opened, he felt far worse than he had pre-nap. His body had gummed up, like tired machinery filled with clotted grease. The cigarette had burned down between his fingers. He threw it out the open window and winched himself upright, using the door handle and the emergency brake for leverage. The sun still hovered well above the horizon, but its warmth was gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Ladies and the Peacemaker&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace started the car and pulled away from the curb with a jerk. As he drove, he tried to decide if he was afraid or not. Something squirmed in his guts, but he couldn’t name it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heading generally north, he crept along. Cars passed by on the left in a steady stream and he found himself leaning forward, practically up to the windshield, trying to bring the moving shapes into some kind of focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace drove for about twenty minutes, his hands tight on the wheel, that energy percolating in his belly. Finally, he found what he was looking for and pulled off the road into a large parking lot. He found a space up near the building and set the emergency brake, but left the car running. These things followed a certain protocol. He looked at the sign in front of the Merc. Handicap only. Well, he didn’t have the tag to hang from the Merc’s rearview any more than he had the state’s permission to operate a motor vehicle, but Eustace could think of a dozen ailments that qualified him for the cripple spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His hands shook badly as he unrolled the pistol from the paper bag, and not all of it was old-man palsy. The Peacemaker gleamed in the winter sunlight. He stared at it for a moment, then broke the ancient firearm open again and checked its rounds one by one. Five minus the one he’d fired into Useless Son’s garage door. Carefully, he shook each bullet out of the gun and onto the Merc’s seat. They made a musical sound bouncing into each other. He picked one up and held it a few inches from his crooked nose. His mouth worked absently as he pondered the bullet. One bullet. Just for him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace put the single round into the Peacemaker and got out of the car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were no guards. That was disappointing. In his memory, there was always a fat guy, or maybe an older fellow like himself, stationed just inside the doors, usually sitting on a stool and trying not to doze off. Missing guard aside, the place hardly even seemed like a bank. No marble, no high ceilings and if there was a vault, Eustace couldn’t see it. Just a long counter, a few cubicles and some bland, barely audible jazz. Ah, but nevermind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman at the front desk smiled at Eustace as he passed. She had that patronizing smirk adults reserved for the very young or the very old. Eustace ignored her and made his way over to the courtesy stand near the tellers, where people could endorse their checks and tally up their deposits. He pulled a blank deposit slip from the stack and, using one of the bank’s pens-on-a-chain, he wrote out a short message, pausing for a moment while his beetle-bored brain tried to spell out “please.” There was an “a” in there somewhere, he thought, but couldn’t say for certain. Eventually, he scribbled over the whole word, deciding that the situation didn’t require that kind of civility anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satisfied with his note, Eustace shuffled over to the line of folks waiting for a teller. His left shoe tapped out a rhythm on the bank’s carpet. When it was finally his turn, Eustace went up to the teller—a cute little thing, or so he half-imagined, not being able to see her very well—and set his deposit slip out on the counter, along with the now-empty grocery bag, which had been tucked under his arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What can I do for you, sir?” the girl said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace looked down the row of tellers and then over his shoulder at the other customers. He tapped the deposit slip. The girl looked at it and cocked her head. Even Eustace could see the shift in her expression, from perky to disbelief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is this a joke?” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace shook his head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir…” the teller said, trailing off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next teller down, an older woman, sensed something amiss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is there a problem, Heather?” the older woman said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This man, he…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heather handed the note to the older woman. It took her a moment to decipher Eustace’s palsied chicken scratch, even though there was really only one thing a note like that could possibly say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir, this isn’t funny. Are you here with someone? Is someone supposed to be watching you?” the older woman said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She thought he was senile. That really got Eustace’s goat. The deposit slip was perfectly clear, handwriting aside. He reached under his suit coat and grabbed hold of the blunderbuss concealed within. In his mind, the gun came free in one smooth motion, but somehow the sight at the end of the barrel got tangled in his waistband and refused to budge. The ladies gawked at him as he yanked, twisting his pants all out of whack. As the Peacemaker finally did come free, it jerked his boxer shorts up into his balls pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nuuugghn,” Eustace moaned, stumbling back from the counter and bringing the pistol up with one hand while the other fluttered down to his injured testicles. The Peacemaker hardly looked like a real firearm; it was too big, half a size out of scale with everything else in the room, including Eustace. Heather screamed and put her hands to her face, like a lady was supposed to when confronted by a mouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sir,”  the older woman said, with a disgusted glance at Heather, “you put that thing down right now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace pulled the hammer back, pointed the Peacemaker at the ceiling and fired. There was a terrific crack and the ceiling tile above Eustace blew apart. White bits, like chunky snow, rained down on his shoulders. Except for the insipid jazz, the whole bank went immediately silent. He’d left the other bullets in the car because he didn’t want to hurt anyone, not even by accident, but there was no way he’d rob a bank without shooting the ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Madam,” Eustace said, his voice clear and strong, “put the money in the bag and no one gets hurt. Understand?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hadn’t he spent his whole life wanting to say those words in earnest? Hadn’t every man? Oh, it was fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do what the man says, Heather,” the older woman said, “just stay calm, sir, alright?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace was calm. He was also out of ammunition now, but the tellers didn’t know that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heather emptied her cash drawer into the brown paper bag, and then handed it to the older woman, who did the same, including a bunch of rolled coins. There were two other tellers further down the counter, but Eustace snatched the bag before she could hand it on to them. The sack had a nice heft—a couple of cats, maybe. Eustace wondered how much he was making off with. It was a simple curiosity, not greed. Ten dollars or ten thousand, it made no nevermind to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving at top speed—a considerable effort for meager result—Eustace headed for the door. No one got in his way. Some folks even dropped to the floor with their hands over their heads, which was fine with Eustace, even though it wasn’t strictly necessary. When he finally reached the exit, a man in a shirt and tie actually held the door open for him. Eustace sketched a little salute with his left hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Getaway&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside, the Merc, now the Getaway Car, waited for him, idling in the cripple spot. He flung open the door and lowered himself in, cackling. His bones hardly hurt at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He popped the Merc into reverse and stomped on the gas. The old girl’s tires squealed—actually squealed!—and he clipped the car parked next to him, knocking the rearview mirror off and drawing a long black scratch across its doors. Two people had emerged from the bank, probably to get a look at the Merc’s plates. Let them look. Maybe they’d go and arrest Useless Son.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his excitement, Eustace lost track of the arrows directing him out of the parking lot and wound up driving a quick lap around a vacuum repair shop, before simply plowing over a low concrete planter filled with evergreen bushes and back out onto the main drag. The car bucked and swayed, throwing Eustace up against the rotting headliner and then sliding him across the seat so hard that he lost contact with the pedals and the engine stalled, leaving the Merc sprawled across two lanes of traffic while he crawled back behind the wheel and started her back up and people behind him honked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had no escape route planned. He just went, plunging straight ahead, ignoring red lights and yield signs. People swerved out of his way, their shouts dopplering in his wake. Swinging wide around a corner, he came within a half second of t-boning a minivan, but he swerved and got clear. The Merc, built in the days when gas could safely be guzzled, accelerated steadily, her wheezy guts really warming up for the first time in a long, long while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cops found him pretty quickly. They filled the rearview mirror with red and blue lights like fireworks on the fourth of July, but they couldn’t catch him. The Merc was a blur, a comet. Eventually, the road met an interstate highway and Eustace swerved across two lanes to make the onramp. The cops howled in pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He headed west, up into the mountains, four nearly-empty lanes of pristine blacktop. Traffic had snarled in the eastbound lanes, a stream of headlights in the growing dusk, worker bees headed home after a long day making honey for a queen they had probably never met. Eustace could imagine all those tired faces turning to watch his black Merc scream past, tailed by the cop cars and their flashing lights. It was a high speed chase, by God! Something to tell the wife about over supper that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mountains ahead formed a jagged blue wall against the horizon, but the freeway went through them and all the way out into Utah. That was a lot of blacktop. Sadly, he was never going to see it. The Merc couldn’t hope to outrun the police cruisers forever. Worse, exhaustion was gaining on Eustace faster than the cops were gaining on his car. This needed an ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Eustace was more or less letting the car drive herself by this point, he didn’t see any real harm in letting go of the steering wheel entirely. He grabbed the paper bag filled with his loot and ripped it open. Bills, some of them banded together, others loose, spilled onto his lap along with a silver cascade of change. How much had he owed the bank? It had seemed like a lot back then, but with out-of-control inflation that jerked a nickel bottle of Coke up to a dollar and some, maybe what he had in his lap came somewhere close to the amount they had taken his house for. Even-stevens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ha!” Eustace yodeled, throwing his head back for the pure joy of revenge and motion and everything else. A concrete divider appeared before the Merc’s windshield and advanced at an alarming pace, but Eustace corrected his course almost casually and the Merc swerved away with whole inches to spare. He grabbed a fist full of those lose bills with his free hand and threw them out the window. The wind pulled them up into the sky. More moolah followed, just as fast as Eustace could chuck it. Quarters and nickels hit the blacktop and skipped up over the barrier in the middle of the interstate, where they landed on those commuter’s cars like hail, startling their driver’s attention away from the hurtling black Merc. An entire stack of bills splattered like a fragile bird against the windshield of one of the police cars behind him. It’s paper band burst and the bills flapped free, a month’s pay for the two cops inside, blowing away like still-green autumn leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace couldn’t stop cackling. All his life he’d been afraid, when he should have been a pirate. He tossed the last handful of available cash out the window. There was still more, but it was hiding under the floor mats or cruising around the back, riding the eddies moving through the car. One bill wrapped itself around the gearshift, flapping like a tiny flag. He watched it, fascinated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was then that the Merc died. It wasn’t out of gas, nothing temporary like that. A &lt;em&gt;thunk&lt;/em&gt; rocked the car, he felt it through the seat, and then the engine just cut out. Probably a rod come loose. She was done. Being both a professional mechanic and as old as he was made Eustace an expert at fatal sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shifted into neutral. At the moment of death they had been cruising along at eighty-five miles per hour. Not so shabby, but the freeway up into the mountains was steep and the Merc’s momentum bled away fast. Sixty, then fifty, then forty. Eustace pulled over to the shoulder and flipped on the emergency blinkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cop cars formed up in a wide file behind the Merc, blocking off traffic. Eustace could see more flashing lights coming down from the mountains, eastbound in the westbound lanes. In just a few minutes they would have him surrounded. Good, good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Put your hands on the wheel,” a voice bellowed so loudly that Eustace was momentarily startled into thinking God had spoken to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the policemen advanced on the car, crouched over with their guns pointed at the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just then, something next to Eustace exploded with a loud &lt;em&gt;thump&lt;/em&gt; and suddenly the car was full of purple paint. It had gotten all over him, too. They did that. Put dye bombs in with the stolen loot. He’d seen it in movies. Why it had waited this long to go off, Eustace didn’t know. He started to laugh so hard that he couldn’t breathe, tears rolling down his cheeks. Until just then, he wouldn’t have guessed his body contained enough moisture for tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Put your hands on the wheel,” the voice said again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace considered the gun on the seat next to him. It wasn’t loaded, but it could still serve a purpose, if he wanted it to. He could pick it up one last time. He could finish what he had started. He could go out in a hail of gunfire. It was phrase that stung like clean whiskey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, was he done? The cops were there, waiting. Eustace looked at the Peacemaker. Put a hand on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Merc’s door swung open and Eustace emerged, one limb at a time, struggling to extract himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Stop,” the voice howled, “or we will shoot!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace did not stop. He pulled himself up to his full six feet (minus a few inches on account of his hump), in front of all those lights. He wouldn’t stop, not until they made him. Addled by exhaustion and the first squirts of adrenaline he’d enjoyed in many a long year, Eustace wasn’t sure they &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; stop him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was something he’d learned when he was in the army, something a crazy Brit special forces guy had shown him. The Brit way of flipping someone off. It was the same thing Nixon did, only reversed, the back of the fingers out, instead of in. The way he understood it, the French once made a habit of cutting off their British captives’ first two fingers so they couldn’t shoot a longbow in war anymore. So, showing an enemy your two fingers in that wide V shape meant you were still dangerous, still able to put an arrow though a man’s heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He raised his gun hand, those two fingers up and spread, covered in purple dye. But he didn’t have the Peacemaker. It was still in the Merc. He stood there, rigidly at attention, saluting the cops with his two fingers until they put the cuffs on him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turned out, he wasn’t done after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The judge called Eustace an audacious criminal and furthermore the oldest bank robber on record, which tickled Eustace just to death. He clapped his hands together and cawed his old man laugh and goddamned if that judge didn’t smile a little bit as he banged the gavel down. Right there was a moment Eustace would have hated to miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it wasn’t the last. They put Eustace in with a young buck, just fifty-one, serving time for counterfeiting and robbery and assault and murder and Lord knew what else. He was Mexican, with a little South American Dictator’s pencil mustache, but he spoke English pretty good. Since there was nothing else to do in the cell, Jesus (that was HEY-soos, not GEE-zus) sometimes told stories about the his adventures on the outside, screwing and shooting and outsmarting just about everyone. Eustace had no idea how many of Jesus’s stories were true, how many were co-opted from someone else and how many were plain make-believe, but the Mexican paced the floor of their cell like a tiger as he spun them, acting out the interesting parts, and wasn’t that better than a comatose roommate who only announced his presence by shitting himself? To quote Shirley, you betcha it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eustace knew what was supposed to happen in prison—shower room things—and a little of that went on, but mostly it went on between guys who were into it and anyway no one ever bothered him, probably because he looked like a day-glow stick of beef jerky in his orange prison uniform. On the few occasions someone gave him any hassle, Jesus and his Mexican buddies took care of it, because Jesus liked him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It got boring sometimes, but boredom was an old friend of his. To kill that old friend, he could watch television or read. The food was even good—well, better than it had been at the Eldercare because it actually had salt in it—and they let him smoke, a verboten activity at the home. He paid for the cigs out of money he made swabbing out the bathrooms. He enjoyed that. He liked having a purpose again, even if it was scrubbing down stainless-steel johns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He would probably serve out his life here, however much of it remained. Or maybe not. Either way, he didn’t mind. He almost never thought about that Peacemaker and the messy deliverance it had once offered. Because there were prisons, and there were prisons.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zbell</name></author><category term="content" /><summary type="html">Old, embittered and depressed, Eustace decides to kill himself. Then he does something else.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Taking Pictures of Cats Having Sex In Istanbul</title><link href="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/09/21/taking-pictures-of-cats-having-sex-in-istanbul.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking Pictures of Cats Having Sex In Istanbul" /><published>2015-09-21T23:26:31-06:00</published><updated>2015-09-21T23:26:31-06:00</updated><id>https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/09/21/taking-pictures-of-cats-having-sex-in-istanbul</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/09/21/taking-pictures-of-cats-having-sex-in-istanbul.html">&lt;p&gt;Whenever anyone he knows goes abroad, my brother asks them to buy him foreign fetish porn. Some examples: bondage, lactation, hentai, large women sitting on skinny men, goats (or any farm animals) wearing latex. He does this on the pretense that the exercise will encourage the traveler to engage in genuine, meaningful, enlightening cross-cultural…something.  Cross-cultural sex-offender convictions, likely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since guidebooks generally don’t include how to say, “Where you keepin’ them fukbooks with the gals in clown makeup?” in Norwegian, these “conversations” (and some people have actually fallen for his line of crap) must also include pantomime and that’s what my brother is really after: nothing makes him happier than a little absurdity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also likes weird porn.  He&amp;#39;s working on many levels, all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it gets relevant here in a moment, you also need to know that my brother is sort of a neophyte cat lady.  He owns two, talks about adopting more and even bought an enclosed baby stroller/bike trailer to take his otherwise indoor felines on tours of the neighborhood, safely enclosed by the trailer’s mesh sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we went to Turkey this summer and, as usual, my brother asked me to bring him home some foreign fetish porn. I told him no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it was our first night in Istanbul and the people I was traveling with were all dead from jet lag and the general stress of traveling, so after dinner I left them at the hotel and went for a walk through the Old City by myself, armed with a backpack full of camera equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ayasofyamuzesi.gov.tr/en&quot;&gt;Hagia Sophia&lt;/a&gt;, an ancient Cathedral built by the Byzantines in 500 AD, a church nearly as old as Christianity itself, that I happened across a wrought iron fence surrounding an empty lot that was infested with cats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahh, the elements of the title come together now, don’t they?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along this fence, on a raised concrete wall that extended up to about eye level, two cats were getting their freak on.  Have you ever seen cats making kittens?  It’s the kind of sex I-cut-myself-just-to-feel-something girls have with boys whose daddies made them join the Hitler Youth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s biologically mandated sexual assault.  Daddy-cat bites mommy-cat on the neck while she tries to claw his face off and there’s just no way to tell if either party is enjoying themselves, but as animals go, at least it isn’t the usual disinterested three seconds of pumping.  Kitties know how to put on a show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I watched, it occurred to me that here was my brother&amp;#39;s Turkish porn.  Equipped as I was with a semi-professional photography outfit, I proceeded to document the beautiful event.  The cats didn’t mind.  They let me get right up close and, being the obsessive-compulsive that I am, a simple snapshot wouldn’t suffice when I could get a Pulitzer-quality photo of, well, cats fucking.  I wanted the perfect shot, him biting, her mid-yowl, the very definition of lust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You thought my brother strange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly across a narrow street from the fence stood the Istanbul Hilton.  With a doorman.  I heard him yelling something, presumably at me, but I don’t generally stop taking photos until yelling escalates to shouting and then the cop showed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was I doing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing much, officer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cop proceeded to explain—via a series of world weary, disappointed frowns—that in Turkey people do not take pictures of cats having sex because it is a gross thing to do.  I defended myself by saying that the pictures were not for my own gratification and that I was merely a player in some sort of cross-continental performance art orchestrated by my brother.  An innocent, in other words and please don’t send me to Turkish prison as I have heard really bad things about Turkish prisons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He did not arrest me, but he did make me delete every picture of the copulating cats.  The few pictures I had of the other cats on the wall—the cats not having sex—he let me keep, even giving a thumbs up to those photos and smiling, the way a parent might after a toddler manages to use the toilet instead of filling their pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We go abroad as cultural ambassadors.  It’s likely that I am the only American some people will ever meet.  It warms me to know that I have done my country proud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to add that my brother is absolutely right: the value of travel for travel’s sake is in the stories you bring home. No one cares if you saw the Mona Lisa. Seek the fetish porn and see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zbell</name></author><category term="content" /><summary type="html">Wherein I travel to distant lands, try to get a nice souvenir and then engage in philosophical debate with policeman.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Travelers, To Dublin</title><link href="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/09/18/welcome-travelers-to-dublin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Travelers, To Dublin" /><published>2015-09-18T12:07:12-06:00</published><updated>2015-09-18T12:07:12-06:00</updated><id>https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/09/18/welcome-travelers-to-dublin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/09/18/welcome-travelers-to-dublin.html">&lt;p&gt;We lived in Loughborough, a grumpy, brick-and-gloom sort of place somewhere in the middle of England, and my family was back home in Colorado. We hadn’t seen each other for a while, so they—my parents and my brother—decided to come for a visit. Since Loughborough doesn&amp;#39;t have any particular sights to see,&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;Here’s the entirety of the tourism section from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Loughborough#Tourism&quot;&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; on Loughborough: ”In 1841, Loughborough was the destination for the first package tour, organised by Thomas Cook for a temperance group from Leicester.” That’s about as good as it gets in Loughborough&lt;/span&gt; we decided to go to meet in Ireland. When we arrived, they were already waiting for us at the the airport. Everyone hugged, we collected our baggage. Then we realized that it was late—well past midnight—and that the trains had stopped running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Let&amp;#39;s get a cab,&amp;quot; I said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just then a double-decker bus rolled up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ooooooh,” my mother said.  An American tourist fresh off the plane cannot resist a double-decker bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Seriously. Let’s take a cab,” I said. I get sick on buses. I also get seasick, trainsick, ferriswheelsick and pogosick. The double-deckers are the worst; it&amp;#39;s like riding out swells in a crow&amp;#39;s nest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humbug. My mother was in Ireland now and by God, she was going to ride the double-decker bus. So we got on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are some seats there, behind the driver,” I suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Second floor!” my mother demanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up the stairs we went, burdened with a pair of large duffel bags and a flock of those wheely suitcases. A couple of unsmiling Filipino maids sat in the front row and a trio of teenage boys were near the back, passing a joint and giggling. Someone is always smoking a joint on the upper deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello Americans!” the teenagers said, upon hearing our accents. They stowed the joint, in deference to my mother, who glared at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Are you Justin Timberlake?” one said to my brother. Though slouchy and predisposed to dress like a homeless man, my brother does look a little like Timberlake, especially at night, while wearing an uncharacteristically preppy souvenir Guinness sweater he’d bought after his tour of the factory earlier that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sing something, Justin!” the Irish lads demanded. To help him along, the Irish lads broke into a their own version of &lt;em&gt;Rock Your Body&lt;/em&gt;, with perfect, clear Irish voices, even singing in the round for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t be so quick, don’t be so quick, don’t be so quick…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To walk away!” my brother croaked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father had no idea who the Backstreet Boys were, but he joined in the singing. So did my wife and I. Even stoned almost past walking, the lads were charming. By that point, only the Filipino maids and my mother were still silent, the maids keeping a wary eye on things and my mother—who is not a social creature—staring straight ahead, one of the duffel bags set squarely on the floor between her knees. The experience of riding the Irish bus was being thoroughly ruined for her by the presence of the Irish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few stops later another man got on and wove his way up the spiral staircase. He glared amicably at everyone and then settled in at the very back, bottle in hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That man is drunk, Justin,” one of the Irish lads whispered conspiratorially to my brother. “I’m sorry for that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes,” one of the other lads agreed, “a drunk Irishman. And I’m a leprechaun. Welcome to Dublin.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did you know that this one here,” one Irish lad put his arm around his friend’s shoulders, “was once in a sausage commercial?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hadn’t known that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s true,” the other lad admitted, “I debated trading my grandma for sausages.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In the commercial,” the first lad clarified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m almost as famous as you, Justin,” the second lad said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s right. Don’t be so fast,”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To walk away,” my brother croaked. The Irish lads decamped from their bench and joined my brother on his, displaying the sort of instant European camaraderie that creeps Americans out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fuckya,” the drunk said from the back. It wasn&amp;#39;t clear if he was into the singing or trying to pick a fight. The Irish lads pointedly ignored him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few stops later, while my brother and the lads sang more Timberlake, another drunk got onto the bus and he put the first drunk to shame. He was not merely swaying, but &lt;em&gt;slamming&lt;/em&gt; from one side of the isle to the other while flailing his arms around. He had a bag of McDonald’s in one hand and a super-size Coke in the other. Finally, and maybe this should have led the list, the man was wearing a white jumpsuit covered in blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t as if he was bleeding on himself. This was definitely someone else’s blood. There were handprints and long streaks where he had wiped his palms. Maybe he was a butcher. Maybe he had spent the evening dismembering his victims in a basement. Whatever it was, it had driven him to drink. The physical force of his drunk-waves stunned even the Irish lads into temporary silence. He grinned at everyone and then settled into the back of the bus, next to the earlier drunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jaaaaayzuz,” one of the Irish lads said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Looks like he should have a knife and onna those hockey masks, right?” the second Irish lad said,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I want to assure you that the gentleman back there is not a representative of the Irish people,” the third Irish lad said with a stoned sincerity. “You’re going to have a lovely holiday. Don’t worry.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus rolled on. The Irish lads told us more about the sausage commercial and sang songs with my brother. They demonstrated how their brogues could quickly dissolve into something completely unlike English and then quizzed us on the gibberish shooting out of their mouths. Slowly, I became aware of a new sound, faintly at first, then louder: running water. It was like a fountain, a happy splashing that went on and on. And on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took a moment to figure out what was happening and, even then, accounts vary. One of the drunks, either the blood-covered man, or the more nondescript drunk, was pissing against the back of the seat in front of him. I say it was the nondescript drunk, but my wife insists it was the man in the blood-covered jumpsuit. Perhaps, and this is a radical theory, it was both of them simultaneously. It was a lot of piss. They were both smiling at everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Aaaaahhh, noevnanafukinbloosh!” one of the Irish lads declared, hopping up on top of the bench&lt;span class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;Rough translation from the origional Irish: ‘Not even a fucking blush!’.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The piss found the aisle and sloshed laterally as the bus went around a corner. My wife, my father, my brother and I all hauled ourselves and our luggage up onto the benches and out of harm&amp;#39;s way, but my mother, who had been vigorously ignoring everything around her for the last forty minutes, stared directly ahead, the duffel bag still planted firmly on the floor between her feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mom!” my brother said, reaching forward to shake her shoulder. “Mom!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No luck. The piss rolled under our seats, so fresh that it had a head to it, like beer it had so recently been. It hit the bottom of the duffel bag—my duffel bag as it happened—two inches deep and swept around my mother’s shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Noevenablush!” the Irish lad shouted again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Filipino maids had chosen to adopt my mother’s ignore-it-and-it-might-go-away tactics, but they knew to raise their feet. Then the bus accelerated and the tide rolled back in, re-soaking the bag and making the Irish lads shout. Piss found the spiral staircase down into the first deck and formed a waterfall like the elevator doors opening in Kubrick’s &lt;em&gt;The Shining&lt;/em&gt;. A pause. Dismayed screams echoed hollowly up from below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every curve, stop sign or hill made the piss dash around like an ugly puppy until, eventually, blessedly, the bus finally arrived at our stop. We hauled our luggage gingerly across the aisle and down the dripping stairs. Urine had made it as far as the yellow do-not-stand-in-front-of-this line. People glared at us, as if we were party to whatever horrorshow had gone on upstairs. When the doors opened, it’s likely that a few drops plipped into the gutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we stepped out of the urine charnel bus and into the slightly sodden night, my brother picked up the duffel bag my mother had failed to save from the drunks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello Dublin!” my brother shouted. “This bag smells like human pee!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wait!” one of the Irish lads called after us. He had hopped off the bus and now he trotted up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is my old neighborhood,” he explained, “and I know just where your hotel is. I’ll show you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, thank you,” my mother said, society-polite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah thanks,” my brother said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ain’t no thing, Justin,” he said, mistaking Hollywood black for American, as many in Europe will do. It&amp;#39;s either black or cowboy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Irish lad was terribly, genuinely embarrassed. He gave us a midnight tour of the neighborhood as we tramped over to the hotel. He apologized on the drunks’ behalf. He shook all of our hands in front of the hotel. He offered to give us his cell phone number in case we needed anything while we were in Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What none of us told him—what we didn’t have the words or time to express—was that we had all loved the bus ride. That it had been my family’s idea of a perfect evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone except my mother, but she would recover. She always does.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zbell</name></author><category term="content" /><summary type="html">We took this double-decker bus and maybe someone got murdered and then my mom didn't save my luggage from disaster.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alfreds For Breakfast</title><link href="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/08/27/alfreds-for-breakfast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alfreds For Breakfast" /><published>2015-08-27T18:45:29-06:00</published><updated>2015-08-27T18:45:29-06:00</updated><id>https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/08/27/alfreds-for-breakfast</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/08/27/alfreds-for-breakfast.html">&lt;p&gt;When George walked into the diner, Albert was already on his stool, bent over a sheet of paper, laboriously writing with a stub of a pencil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Best finish that homework, Albert,” George said, seating himself two stools down, “Bus’ll be here soon.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shut up,” Albert said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s he doing?” George said to Patrice as she came by with his coffee. It was early and George and Albert were the diner’s only customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s writing to a school board in Dallas. You want the usual?” Patrice said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh. Yeah, usual’s fine,” George said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Coming right up.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrice slapped the bell and Javier, somewhere out of sight in the kitchen, grunted a sleepy reply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pat?” George said after a moment&amp;#39;s consideration, “Albert know we live in Omaha?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Probably.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George glanced at Albert, who glared back in that way he had of glaring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So Pat? Why’s Albert writing a school board in Texas?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s trying to get the theory of plate tectonics removed from high school textbooks,” Pat said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Now comes the part where I ask why he’d do such a fool thing, but I ain’t gonna, because I don’t care.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Texas can apparently dictate text book guidelines on account of it being such a big state,” Patrice said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Huh,” George said. He sipped loudly from his coffee. The moment stretched out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Ask, goddamnit,&amp;quot; Albert said, still glaring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’ve you got against plate tectonics, Albert?” George finally said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing. I’m continental drift’s biggest fan,” Albert said, returning to his letter. He wrote with the single-minded squint of a second grader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, a theory hasn’t really hit its stride until some chromosome-poor jaw-tumor tries to get it removed from the curriculum.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Which is what you’re doing now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Alfred Wegener was a badass, dog eating, arctic son of a bitch. I want half the people drawing X&amp;#39;s on his grave and the other half forming a mob to dig up his corpse and put it on trial posthumously.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than ask Alfred for clarification on any of this—never a good idea—George looked over at Patrice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Alfred Wegner is the fella that first came up with the idea of continental drift,” Patrice offered, “ain’t that just what we need? Another Alfred, I mean.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes. The more Alfreds the better,” Alfred said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did you just know that Wegner guy’s name, Pat? Am I the only ignoramus here?” George said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No no,&amp;quot; Patrice said, &amp;quot;I’ve been listening to our Albert go on for almost an hour now. It’s been an unwilling education.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Alfred Wegner&amp;#39;s name should be there with Charles Darwin, but it&amp;#39;s never going to be until he’s been properly vilified. Problem is, I don’t think the anti-evolution idiots understand enough about plate tectonics to get a good religious panic going.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don&amp;#39;t recall that the Bible has a lot to say about continental drift,” George said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Plate tectonics is at least partially responsible for most speciation. We have kangaroos in Australia and llamas in Peru because the continents drifted apart. So there&amp;#39;s an evolution angle. It doesn&amp;#39;t allow for any young-earth bullshit either, because a hundred thousand years is an afternoon&amp;#39;s nap for a continent. That should be more than enough to contradict some Biblical bibble-babble.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You&amp;#39;re getting diatribe all over my eggs,” George groused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Albert waved him off with an imperious, graphite-smudged hand and went back to sermonizing,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They threw Galileo into a tower and everyone knows who Darwin was. Drew him with an ape body and today we’re still arguing  evolution vs. bedtime stories.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It wasn’t scandal that immortalized Darwin, it was the elegance of—” George ventured, but Albert verbally shoved him aside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Reactionary idiots dumped ice water on Ed Wilson&amp;#39;s head for sociobiology. That&amp;#39;s not a Snopes Monkey Trial, but at least it&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, out of a sense of...fairness, you want this this other Albert, the Wegener fella, you want his name removed from textbooks?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No. I want someone to &lt;em&gt;try&lt;/em&gt; to remove his name from the textbooks. Until your ideas have made a racing fan, be they NASCAR or chariot, wonder if they really will see grandma in candyland after they die, then you haven’t arrived. Vilification is vindication. A parable.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alfred accompanied this speech with waggles of his pencil, as if directing the motley orchestra of his mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You believe that, huh?” George said. Patrice slid his eggs across the counter with an eye-roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The theory of plate tectonics is one of the most elegant, important ideas man has ever had,&amp;quot; Alfred said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I ain’t disagreeing,&amp;quot; George said, &amp;quot;but maybe the idea itself matters more than getting full credit.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Pssh,” Alfred said, dismissively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Alright, well hold on a minute, let me…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;George dug his Otter-boxed phone out of his pocket and poked at the battered screen for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Alright, yes, here. Alfred Wallace, just as an example.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrice, who had been half-following the conversation, turned around, her hands on her hips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Great,” she said, “yet another Alfred.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh yeah,” George said, “Didn’t even think of that until after I said it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, who’s this one?” Patrice said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He’s the guy that came up with the idea of evolution at the same time Darwin did, but never got the same recognition. The man wound up spending his life in Darwin’s shadow, actually defending Darwin&amp;#39;s &lt;em&gt;Origin&lt;/em&gt;. Don’t think he was bitter though. Didn’t want to be famous, particularly. I think he was happy enough in just knowing the idea got loose. Science should exist separate to society and politics whenever it can. If plate techtonics is a done deal, then leave it be.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Alfred &lt;em&gt;Wegener&lt;/em&gt; risked his life for answers,” Alfred interrupted, “The man went to the Arctic for the sake of science. He got frostbite and cut his toes off with a penknife. When the expedition ran out of food, he killed and ate his sled dogs—&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I was wondering about the dog-eating part,&amp;quot; George said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;—and he eventually died up there in Greenland. He died for &lt;em&gt;science&lt;/em&gt;. I want to see him enter the canon for his achievements. By name. Alfred Wegener”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Got nothing to do with him having your name?&amp;quot; Patrice said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Maybe a little,” Albert said, returning to the letter.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ratlaf</name></author><category term="content" /><summary type="html">Albert wants to get the man who proposed plate tectonics removed from highschool textbooks.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Juney’s Coming For A Visit</title><link href="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/08/21/juneys-coming-for-a-visit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Juney's Coming For A Visit" /><published>2015-08-21T23:26:31-06:00</published><updated>2015-08-21T23:26:31-06:00</updated><id>https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/08/21/juneys-coming-for-a-visit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/08/21/juneys-coming-for-a-visit.html">&lt;p&gt;A bell over the diner&amp;#39;s door rang as George walked in.  The sound, Pavlovian, reminded him to remove his baseball cap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place had once been a Waffle House, but then a bad economy had landed on the town a few years back, the way locusts alight on a hayfield and that was the end of the Waffle House, along with just about everything else.  Now the place was a no-name joint.  A banner had been hung across the original yellow sign and that banner read &amp;#39;BREAKFAST,&amp;#39; with no elaboration or lies.  Someone had taken a stab at painting fried eggs and bacon on the windows, and the result got the point across, though the two yolks looked a little like the wide-eyed stare of a distant (and possibly stoned) Aztec god and the stiff bacon parked on the edge of the plate seemed vaguely sexual with its browns and pinks.  A rank of chipped wood-pattern Formica counter tops ran between the dining area and the kitchen.  Coffee machines old enough for Medicaid stood watch over miniature boxes of Frosted Flakes.  The juke box had broken down, but no one had the heart to haul it away.  A diner is a lesser place with no jukebox.  That said, no one longed for the days when it could still play &amp;#39;A Waffle House Christmas&amp;#39; either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Morning, George,” the waitress, Patrice, said from behind the counter.  She owned the place and, while her restaurant would never attempt to take on even a single pretension, she kept it scrupulously clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Morning, Patrice,” George said.  He stuffed the hat indifferently into the back pocket of his jeans, bill first, and had a seat at one of the stools by the counter.  He was a tall man, too tall for the stool, and with his feet up on the rail under the counter, he seemed out of scale with his surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Morning, George,” said a fat man perched two stools down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Morning Alfred,” George said to the fat man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s shaking, George?” Patrice said, setting a mug of coffee in front of him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Daughter called last night.  She’s coming for Christmas after all.  Her‘n the kids.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bible Babe, or the one with the,” Alfred made a circling motion around his face with an extended finger.  He meant port-wine stain, which George’s younger daughter—April—did have, though it was no bigger than a soup can and mostly hidden behind her hairline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Juney.  The uhhh...the religious one, yeah,” George said morosely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thought they couldn’t afford it this year?” Patrice said.  She was a short, man-faced woman with no-nonsense hair and capable hands.  Put her in a pantsuit, Alfred once said, and she’d make a good political appointee.  Put her in a mullet and she’d make a good dog washer.  Alfred generally tuned his considerable brains towards snide, the way Newton had directed his to the subject of gravity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, they got ahold of some free plane tickets, somehow,” George said, “prayed for em, maybe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well don’t bring them here,” Alfred mumbled around a forkload of eggs and Tobasco sauce, “find somewhere else for breakfast.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s just rude, Alfred,” Patrice said with one hand on her cocked hip, “Man’s welcome here and so’s his family.  And you want to know something else, Alfred Mendis?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Probably not,” Alfred said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re a real bastard and that’s why no one loves you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, okay, actually I did know that,” Alfred said, belching into his fist.  Alfred spent nine months of the year on a derrick in the Gulf, ‘doing Satan’s Petrochemical will,’ as he put it.  The empty time between stints made him ornery, especially in first few weeks ashore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They won’t eat at restaurants anyway,” George said, “Juney’ll cook everything.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?  Is the smell of a greasy spoon is offensive to the Lord?” Alfred said, shoveling another heap of yolk-bleeding egg into his mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not exactly,” George said, “Mostly they got five kids now and—“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Five?” Patrice said, “Thought it was four.  I must have lost track somewhere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“—yeah, they had another baby this summer. I haven’t met that one yet. Anyway, they can’t afford to eat out.  That and Jacob is convinced that Mexicans will spit in his food on account of his being a white man.  Sorry, Javier.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Javier, the cook, leaned out through his order window. This early in the morning, his chef whites still had a perky, just-out-of-the dryer crispness to them that wouldn’t last past ten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Hey, yeah man, it&amp;#39;s true, we will,” the cook drawled. “We’ll spit in your food. All of us,&amp;quot; Javier said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, that’s fucking great,” Albert said, and then he laughed, like really thought it was great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Yeah,” Javier continued, “It&amp;#39;s a racial thing.  A racist thing.  Whatever.&amp;quot;   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please,” Patrice said, “Javier, don&amp;#39;t even joke.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, okay. I’m joking. I only spit in the cops’ food.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?” Patrice said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Actually, it&amp;#39;s only that deputy with the limp.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Dougie Franks?  What he ever do to you?” George said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Remember that INS raid at the Tyson Chicken Plant a few months back?  Well, my cousin Maria, she—&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She worked there?  Your cousin an illegal?” Alfred said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Javier snorted. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She’s an accountant over in Carverville and she married a guy who teaches rice how to gringo. They go clog dancing because he’s Polish or something.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;So...&amp;quot; Alfred said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;So, Maria was also having an affair with Deputy Dragleg. With Dougie.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Wow,” George said.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t see the problem, unless you&amp;#39;re upset on her husband’s behalf,” Alfred said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, who cares about him?  See, what got me mad was that Dougie knew about the raid on Tyson&amp;#39;s chicken morgue, but he didn&amp;#39;t say nothing to Maria about it.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;So?&amp;quot; Alfred said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Well, my cousin&amp;#39;s got cousins too, about a million, and a bunch of them worked out at Tyson.  There&amp;#39;s this one girl in particular, named Rosa.  My cousin and her grew up together—”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So Maria is from Mexico?” Albert interrupted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No. Her people come out of California like nine generations back. They been there so long they should form up their own INS and send all you gringos back to wherever the hell you came from.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then how did she grow up with this Rosa?” Albert said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Because Rosa’s parents came over when she was a kid. She grew up in Cali too.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gotcha,” Albert said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Anyway, Rosa had a job yanking guts out of chickens but since Dougie kept the raid a secret, now Rosa didn&amp;#39;t know to lie low and so she got sent back to Mexico.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Did you even know this Rosa?” Alfred said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah kinda. I didn’t like her, but see, while she’s gone, Maria has to take care of Rosa’s kid, who’s a real brat.“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So because your cousin’s side of bacon didn’t tell her about the raid, your, like, ninth cousin seventeen times removed got punted back to Juarez for a few months and that’s why you spit in Dougie&amp;#39;s eggs?” Alfred said.  He popped an entire triangle of toast into his mouth and set to munching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No. I’m getting there. Maria wants to get rid of Rosa’s kid, because he’s a real brat.  He doesn’t speak any damned English and fights with Rosa’s honkey husband all the time, but his momma ain&amp;#39;t going come back and take him off their hands until she can afford another coyote, which will be never, because Rosa ain&amp;#39;t got a job. Nobody down there has a job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So before she comes back, Rosa wants Maria to give her the money for the coyote. So here comes Maria and she needs me to make a contribution to the bring-Rosa-home fund. It’s like a kidnapping ransom, only in reverse and I told her that Rosa’s been deported a few times before and she probably  knows the way back by now, but Anita won’t shut up about her cousin dying of thirst out in the desert and how that would be my fault, so I give her the money.  It was worth it just for the quiet, except then I didn&amp;#39;t have nothing left to pay the cable bill and so they come out to my place and take all the good channels away so I can&amp;#39;t watch football no more.  &lt;em&gt;That’s&lt;/em&gt; why I spit in the cop’s eggs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Doesn’t really seem like it’s Dougie&amp;#39;s fault,” George ventured after a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Gotta be somebody’s fault, don’t it?” Javier said, “After the raid, Tyson hired up a bunch of fresh Mexicans, all of em illegals, none of em my cousin.  The chickens still get their guts pulled out, same as before.  The cops didn&amp;#39;t get a medal or a reward or a raise or anything.  Nothing changed, ‘cept somehow I missed the Vikings game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If the CEO of Tyson or any of those Mexicans they hired stops by for a bite, I’ll spit in their food too.  If one of those INS bastards shows up with his stupid jacket, I’ll take a dump in that bastard&amp;#39;s mouth. Until then, I do what I can and fuck anyone who says different.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s funny,” Alfred said meditatively, “but every time a spic on TV gets all riled up, they start throwing random Mexican into their sentences.  Do you even know Spanish, Javier?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey, fuck you,” Javier said, waving his spatula in a warning fashion through the order window, “and I said ‘gringo’ in there somewhere.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And you’re ok with your employees spitting in an officer of the law’s food?” Alfred said to Patrice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrice shrugged a whadyagonnado shrug.  “I know Dougie’s wife.  She’s a real sweetheart.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A silence fell on the otherwise empty restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, anyway, Juney’s coming,” George said.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zbell</name></author><category term="content" /><summary type="html">George's daughter will be in town for Christmas, Alfred isn't as racist as he sounds and Javier's cousin is being deported.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You’re Right, But Still</title><link href="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/08/15/youre-right-but-still.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You're Right, But Still" /><published>2015-08-15T17:57:11-06:00</published><updated>2015-08-15T17:57:11-06:00</updated><id>https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/08/15/youre-right-but-still</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/08/15/youre-right-but-still.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; Okay, Coors, so it&amp;#39;s cool about those twins. I mean yeah, I like twins. Cheerleaders are good too, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; Twins, right? And cheerleaders! Fuckin&amp;#39;-a!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; Thanks to the internet my tastes have evolved into something a little more, uhh, specific, but tits and short skirts still tickle the lizard brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; I got your back, buddy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; Uh huh. Last night I saw your new commercial, you know, where the woman spreads a trail of rose petals across the floor of the kitchen and meets her guy wearing lingerie. She says &amp;#39;like what you see?&amp;#39; to him and he&amp;#39;s like &amp;#39;yeah,&amp;#39; but he&amp;#39;s looking at his beer in the fridge and not her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; The commercial runs counter to expectations. The man ignores the advances of a woman. That&amp;#39;s what makes it funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; I don&amp;#39;t know, she&amp;#39;s horny, or she wants to do something nice for the dude or...I don&amp;#39;t know. Maybe she&amp;#39;s insecure about their relationship. That&amp;#39;s reading a lot into it. Anyway, he&amp;#39;s supposed to be me, right? The everyman so beaten down that not even fucking interests him anymore. She&amp;#39;s a good looking woman, but that guy on the commercial has absolutely no interest in her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes a guy just wants to kick back and have a cold one, right? No hassles!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; No. It&amp;#39;s accurate. Shit&amp;#39;s been bad. I got laid off forever ago. You know that. Money&amp;#39;s tight and the kids, well, I don&amp;#39;t want to talk about the kids. So sex isn&amp;#39;t really a priority for me. Not that my wife spends much time throwing around rose pedals in her underwear. She&amp;#39;s been grabbing all the overtime she can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; You&amp;#39;re making me sad. Don&amp;#39;t do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; How’d you decide to sell beer to my depression and my crotch at the same time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;#39;s the circle of life!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; Mercenary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; Yup. Guilty. If genital warts or suicide sold beer...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; Whatever. Look, as long as a case of Coors costs a buck less than a case of Bud down at the C &amp;amp; J, I&amp;#39;m your loyal drunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; High five!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; You’ve never been able to decide if women are  the uhh…the lady or the tiger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; Huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah, that wasn’t right. The goat or the catamaran? Sexy bear traps? Remember, I am pretty drunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; Not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; Anyway, what bothers me most about the commercial is the last part. The &amp;#39;is your beer cold?&amp;#39; gimmick. Those little things on the can that turn blue? The mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; Cold-Activated bottles and cans: know when your beer is ready to party!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah. I hate those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; Let me guess: you can tell when your beer is cold by touching it? It’s insulting to your intelligence? We caught some of that during the focus testing, but--&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; No. It pisses me off that you’re trying to tell me it matters. Like I could let the beer down by not drinking it right. I&amp;#39;m an out-of-work, nostalgic frat boy with four kids and an on-again-off-again case of impotence. I drink your beer warm while I sit in the garage all by myself and stare into space. Once I left an open can on top of the barbecue grill for three days, rediscovered it, and then drank it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; Whoa, I think--&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; You’re telling me that I can fail at drinking beer too, along with everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; Hey, speaking of drinking it down, I think you&amp;#39;ve killed that soldier. Want another? Look, they&amp;#39;re cold!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;American Male:&lt;/strong&gt; ...yeah, okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coors Beer:&lt;/strong&gt; Great.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zbell</name></author><category term="content" /><summary type="html">A man has a long-overdue conversation with his beer. It's kind of an intervention—in reverse.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bratz Doll Opera</title><link href="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/06/11/a-commentary-enacted-with-bratz-dolls-atop-a-mcdonalds-trashcan-by-an-eight-year-old.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bratz Doll Opera" /><published>2015-06-11T19:00:25-06:00</published><updated>2015-06-11T19:00:25-06:00</updated><id>https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/06/11/a-commentary-enacted-with-bratz-dolls-atop-a-mcdonalds-trashcan-by-an-eight-year-old</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/06/11/a-commentary-enacted-with-bratz-dolls-atop-a-mcdonalds-trashcan-by-an-eight-year-old.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Bratz Doll:&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;#39;s time to play reality show!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second Bratz Doll:&lt;/strong&gt; Cooking or shouting?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First:&lt;/strong&gt; Shut up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second:&lt;/strong&gt; Look at me!  I&amp;#39;m skating!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Second Bratz doll pirouettes across top of McDonald&amp;#39;s trashcan)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second:&lt;/strong&gt; If you want a rose, it&amp;#39;s a game, but I&amp;#39;m going to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First:&lt;/strong&gt; Who&amp;#39;s the faaaaaaatttttest dog?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(First Bratz doll makes barking sounds)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second:&lt;/strong&gt; That&amp;#39;s not enough!  Try harder!  Make it work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First:&lt;/strong&gt; You can&amp;#39;t talk to me that way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Bratz dolls attack one another atop the McDonald&amp;#39;s trashcan)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second:&lt;/strong&gt; I see that skirt!  You stole it.  It&amp;#39;s my design!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Bratz combat continues)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First:&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;#39;m keeping all the stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second:&lt;/strong&gt; Go faster!  You have to go faster!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Bratz dolls collide like bull elk in rut.  The first falls into the trashcan.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second:&lt;/strong&gt; Oh no!  I love you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(The second Bratz doll leaps into the trashcan after the first.  There is a moment of silence.  Girl begins to cry.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mom:&lt;/strong&gt; Angel, come over here and eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Girl peers into trashcan, shrugs, goes off to eat Happy Meal.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ratlaf</name></author><category term="content" /><summary type="html">…performed atop a McDonald’s trashcan by an eight year old.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Landlord</title><link href="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/05/05/landlord.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Landlord" /><published>2015-05-05T18:34:44-06:00</published><updated>2015-05-05T18:34:44-06:00</updated><id>https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/05/05/landlord</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/05/05/landlord.html">&lt;p&gt;The dinosaurs retired the field. Hole-hiding, seed-snuffling mammals poked their snouts into the ash-filled sky and realized they had accidentally inherited everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a race to fill the void opened by the departed dinosaurs and the sloths won. This was on the other side of the ice age. The sloths were not the fastest, not by any measure, but the race doesn&amp;#39;t always honor the fastest. The opposite, in fact. Ask a cheetah about lions. No. The sloths were not fast--they were sloths--but they were the largest. At least some of them. Up on their haunches, these mega-sloths were so tall that only trees could compete with their height. Nothing hunted them. Nothing even tried. Gargantuan, the ends of their forepaws draped with dagger-length claws, sloths had come to the apex of their particular pyramid. They ate what they liked, went where whim took them, mated infrequently because their young almost never died.&amp;lt;!-- more --&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then men came to the frost-tipped plains that had once been icebound but were now merely tundra. They sloths were not impressed. We are suited to the land, the sloths boasted, immune to cold and fang, but the men had spears and a horrifying coordination between their numbers and the sloths were killed and eaten and then gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Men usurped the plains and killed off most everything larger than a dog and what remained--bison and the shyest bears--were either forced to the fringes where the men weren&amp;#39;t, or kept as a sort of self-filling larder. This is the land and we are the land, the men said, meaning that the land was them, but another race was already in progress, again not for speed, but this time not for size either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new men had steel and they dressed in steel instead of feathers. They were armed with muskets and they carried smallpox bred in far-off hive-cities. This is our land, the sloth-and-bison-hunters said, we are formed to it and it to us and the newcomers didn&amp;#39;t love the land, or even see the land, except as a commodity. The land it not beautiful to them. They will not know what they have lost. The new men had not grown against the land, but by steel or disease they took it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new men named the land. Kansas and Oklahoma. They disinterestedly slaughtered the bison and had no memory of sloths that overtopped trees. They laid down poor farms and wrung out the land with cotton that had no business growing in the Midwestern desert. The cotton did grow for a while, but then the rains didn&amp;#39;t come and the men turned to a new creature, larger than sloths, called the Bank. The Bank&amp;#39;s size couldn&amp;#39;t be measured in units of length and it didn&amp;#39;t eat anything that the land produced. The men took out loans from the Bank, hoping to survive, but the rains didn&amp;#39;t come for the third year running and there were no crops and the loans couldn&amp;#39;t be repaid. This is our land, the farmers said as the sheriffs and bulldozers came to evict them, Grandpa fought the Indians here, killed the Indians here. Grandpa died on the land, his bones are buried in the land. The land et Grandpa up and we can&amp;#39;t leave the land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the Bank owned the land and became a creature of the land and called itself Con-Agra. It thought itself immune to races of all sorts. Even insects were not allowed on the Bank&amp;#39;s land, only cotton, only corn, only cattle but the Bank was too large for the land. It drank so much water so that rivers never met the sea. Insatiable, the Bank sucked more water from aquifers that had formed in the time of the sloths until the aquifers were gone. The Bank&amp;#39;s only predator was itself and it died of thirst. Of worse things, symptoms of that thirst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The men who remained took the land again. At first they were armed with remnant silicon, then only steel, then hides and feathers once again. They were farmers with nothing left to grow and ever fewer. No one took the land from them because the land no longer had anything to offer, not without a long rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Farmers, in desperation, in ignorance, became hunters, then scroungers, but there were no sloths, no bison. We could have loved the land better, the men said. All along we could have loved it better. Learned too late, the lesson could not save them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wind inherited the land and the race was delayed for a time. Then a rabbit, not large, nor quick, nor clever, but accepting of death, a rabbit who somehow bred itself around the radiation--was perhaps encouraged by the radiation--sat up on its haunches, checked the sky and sniffed, considering its options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;[Note: This is written with a half-apology to John Steinbeck. I agree with the man almost completely and yet infuriates me as I&amp;#39;m reading. You&amp;#39;re too pat, Mr. Steinbeck, though I like your prose.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, what follows will make a lot more sense if you&amp;#39;ve readThe Grapes of Wrath _ recently. Which you probably haven&amp;#39;t._&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t strive for relevance.]&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zbell</name></author><category term="content" /><summary type="html">This land ain't my land. This land ain't your land.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Heather Died A Long Time Ago</title><link href="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/01/08/heather-died-a-long-time-ago.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Heather Died A Long Time Ago" /><published>2015-01-08T22:46:22-07:00</published><updated>2015-01-08T22:46:22-07:00</updated><id>https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/01/08/heather-died-a-long-time-ago</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://zacharybell.net///content/2015/01/08/heather-died-a-long-time-ago.html">&lt;p&gt;Chad was already on the hill when Millie arrived.  She saw him up there, hands in his pockets, staring down at the ground.  She got out of her car and opened an umbrella against the drizzle.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello,” Chad said as Millie came up behind him.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Lovely weather we&amp;#39;re having,” Millie said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wet grass had soaked through her pumps and the stockings under them.  The rain was very much on her mind. It rained every year.  At first that seemed normal—it was April and it was Washington State—but every year? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chad shrugged.  Millie looked down at the bronze plate, set in a pad of concrete no bigger than a pillowcase.  Heather Paula Fendin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hello, Heather,” Millie said down at the plaque, then, to Chad, “Have you been here long?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Half an hour.  My flight got in mid-morning.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had a day or two’s growth on his cheeks and some of it came in gray.  His temples too.  It hadn’t been there the year before.  Otherwise, he looked about the same.  He wore a suit and patent shoes.  Rain dripped off the longest lock of hair on his forehead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’ve got a little snow on the mountain.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,&amp;quot; Chad said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millie’s own hair would have surrendered entirely to old age some years ago if she didn’t paint it auburn in the sink twice a month.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think you’re the only person I never see dry.  There’s another umbrella in the car, but I don’t suppose you want it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No thank you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Penance?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Something like that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Got a hair shirt under that suit?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He chuckled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How old are you?” Millie said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Thirty-three this December.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So you’ve been coming here longer than…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Longer than she was alive.  I was just thinking about that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I was so angry when I heard you were flying down here every year.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s why I always came two weekends before the…you know, before the fourteenth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;And I was mad at you for being so polite.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I&amp;#39;ll come in March, if you prefer. Or February.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I asked you to come on the fourteenth, didn’t I?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millie remembered the bouquet of lilies in her left hand and bent to set them on the grave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I was so angry about everything.  Angry that you could afford plane tickets.  If you were coming all the way out from New York, then you should have to take the bus. Or walk. Crawl.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sorry.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tears came.  Millie looked up into the rain to hide them.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I saw your picture in the &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt; once.  At some society party to raise awareness about the…who-knows-what.  The manatee, maybe.  I saw that picture and I thought a &lt;em&gt;lawyer&lt;/em&gt;.  A fucking &lt;em&gt;manatee&lt;/em&gt; lawyer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Millie didn’t usually cuss, but now the profanity rolled out smooth and natural.  Chad watched with his hands down in his pockets, the rain falling off of his face.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I thought, ‘he should have married her, not killed her,’” Millie said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He chuckled again. He had a good, textured voice. Deep and somehow comforting, despite his melancholy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Never happen.  She was smarter than I was and she knew it.  I never knew how much she even liked me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You are married, aren’t you? Someone told me that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’d never asked him about his personal life. Not because she didn’t want to know, but because it felt like intruding. He took his hand out of his pocket and showed Millie the ring.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What does your wife think about this?” Millie gestured at the grave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We fight about it ever year,” Chad said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But you still come.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes I do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was handsome, but tired.  The growing creases around his mouth and eyes outlined a hungry, unhappy face. Good, she thought and then mentally took it back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Would you stop coming?  If I asked?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He shook his head.  The rain suddenly doubled, driving divots into the mud.  Neither of them commented on it.  Another moment of silence stretched out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Before she died, I had made my plans,” Chad finally said, “I was going to be a rich guy’s kid.  I was going to be happy with privilege.  I told my dad I would go to law school, but I didn&amp;#39;t mean it.  But then she did die and I…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You became her,” Millie said, “I know.  Manatees.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah.  I did.  She was the one with the treefrog posters and the hemp tennis shoes.  I just played along to get laid.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He looked at her cautiously, from the corner of his eye.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Want to know something else?  While we’re being honest?” Millie said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He laughed low and shoved his hands deeper into his pockets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If you want to tell me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’d stopped coming.  For almost ten years.  At first I would walk up here every day.  Three miles. I did crawl, it felt like. I’d come up here and I’d talk to her and hate you.  Then it was every week and then every month and then just not.  I told myself it hurt too much, but really I just had living to do. I’d take the dog to the park or get my nails done instead.  I got a divorce, I got a new man.  I just stopped coming.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That’s not so bad.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When I heard about what you were doing, I swore that I wouldn’t let you out-mourn me.  But I’m happy.  I can’t stop being happy.  I have her picture on my desk at work, but I don’t remember the last time I looked at it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I keep her prom picture in my wallet.  Even my wife doesn’t know that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But you don’t love her still, I hope.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I never did.  I just killed her.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You didn’t. A telephone pole killed her. A dashboard killed her.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So I became her and you don’t miss her and yet here we are.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chad was crying.  Millie automatically pretended not to notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Death is strange,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not like living, it isn’t.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’ll see you next year then?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Zbell</name></author><category term="content" /><summary type="html">No one can tell you how to mourn.</summary></entry></feed>